<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Press on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/press/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Press on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 20:49:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/press/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Cancer Navigation - GoInvo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/national-cancer-navigation---goinvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 20:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/national-cancer-navigation---goinvo/</guid>
      <description>Mapping cancer journey pain points and exploring how navigation could support patients and their families.&#xA;Read on goinvo.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tell Me Where IT Hurts Podcast: Guest Grace Cordovano, Healthcare Navigating Solutionist, Co-founder of Unblock Health - Medicomp Systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/tell-me-where-it-hurts-podcast--guest-grace-cordovano--healthcare-navigating-solutionist--co-founder-of-unblock-health---medicomp-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 15:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/tell-me-where-it-hurts-podcast--guest-grace-cordovano--healthcare-navigating-solutionist--co-founder-of-unblock-health---medicomp-systems/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to navigating U.S. healthcare, fewer patient experiences are more daunting, frustrating, and confusing than trying to keep all your providers on the same page. Grace Cordovano, PhD &amp;hellip;Continue&#xA;Read on medicomp.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patients want health record access with usability, says Sequoia Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/patients-want-health-record-access-with-usability--says-sequoia-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 20:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/patients-want-health-record-access-with-usability--says-sequoia-project/</guid>
      <description>The interoperability organization&amp;rsquo;s Consumer Voices Workgroup says its recommendations for improving patient access, use and sharing of data are 100% achievable using current technology.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enlightening Results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/enlightening-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 14:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/enlightening-results/</guid>
      <description>I vividly remember walking into my grad school mentor&amp;rsquo;s office, sitting down at the table and chairs, and fretting, &amp;ldquo;Dr. Schramm, I&amp;rsquo;m so torn about what to do: do I pursue the post-doc or do I take the position at this start-up in the city? I absolutely loved bench research, adored biochemist&#xA;Read on enlighteningresults.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Getting Test Results Online Right Away a Good Idea? Yes, Patients Say</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/is-getting-test-results-online-right-away-a-good-idea--yes--patients-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 14:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/is-getting-test-results-online-right-away-a-good-idea--yes--patients-say/</guid>
      <description>But more resources should be available to help them when the news is bad, one expert suggests&#xA;Read on medpagetoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Policy in Practice: Supporting Ready Patient Access to Test Results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/policy-in-practice--supporting-ready-patient-access-to-test-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 18:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/policy-in-practice--supporting-ready-patient-access-to-test-results/</guid>
      <description>MONDAY JUNE 5, 2023 FROM 2:00 3:30 PM ET , Recently, the JAMA Open Network released findings from a March 2023 study showing that most patients preferred to receive their test results immediately online. ONC information blocking regulations support patients access to their electronic test results without unnecessary delay, and the health IT community continues to implement innovative approaches to support such access. Join ONC to hear patient advocates and health IT experts discuss how more immediate access to test results is changing the care paradigm for patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techquity in 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/techquity-in-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 12:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/techquity-in-2023/</guid>
      <description>In 2021, the HLTH Foundation- a 501(c)3 non-profit organization that promotes equity, inclusion, and opportunity in healthcare, strategically partnered with Ipsos- a global market research and advisory firm, to explore the concept of techquity. Together, the teams conducted exploratory industry and patient-focused research for the purpose of bringing attention to the relationship between health equity and health technology and identifying opportunities for the industry to collaborate on addressing techquity gaps -which resulted in an introductory Path to Techquity&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; report and patient ethnography video (published March 2022).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patients need more info, tools and support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/patients-need-more-info--tools-and-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 18:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/patients-need-more-info--tools-and-support/</guid>
      <description>Patients want more trust, transparency and information sharing from healthcare organizations to guide them in their complex healthcare journey, says Grace Cordovano, founder of Enlightening Results.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same Team</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/same-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 12:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/same-team/</guid>
      <description>Doctors and patients are on the same team. Despite how often external forces try to pit us against each other, we all just want to give and receive high-qual&amp;hellip;&#xA;Read on youtube.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why patient burnout is a &#39;silent public health crisis&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/why-patient-burnout-is-a--silent-public-health-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 18:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/why-patient-burnout-is-a--silent-public-health-crisis/</guid>
      <description>At HIMSS23, panelists discuss how providers can boost transparency and patient trust in the healthcare system.&#xA;Read on mobihealthnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Driven Medical Care? A Health Data Reality Check</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/ai-driven-medical-care--a-health-data-reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 12:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/ai-driven-medical-care--a-health-data-reality-check/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The reality is that we have a disaggregated, fragmented system with a lack of organization around common, transparent, high-quality information.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Read on forbes.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sequoia Project Launches Consumer Voices Workgroup To Improve Patient Access to Health Information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/the-sequoia-project-launches-consumer-voices-workgroup-to-improve-patient-access-to-health-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 13:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/the-sequoia-project-launches-consumer-voices-workgroup-to-improve-patient-access-to-health-information/</guid>
      <description>The Sequoia Project, a non-profit and trusted advocate for nationwide health information exchange, launched the Consumer Voices Workgroup to understand first-hand from consumers the barriers they face accessing, using, and sharing their health information and to inform strategies to address the barriers. The non-profit, known for convening industry and government within its Interoperability Matters cooperative, is engaging consumers, patients, care partners, and caregivers for the first time in its pursuit of nationwide seamless, secure health information sharing for better and more effective healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sequoia Project Launches Consumer Voices Workgroup To Improve Patient Access to Health Information - The Sequoia Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/the-sequoia-project-launches-consumer-voices-workgroup-to-improve-patient-access-to-health-information---the-sequoia-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 21:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/the-sequoia-project-launches-consumer-voices-workgroup-to-improve-patient-access-to-health-information---the-sequoia-project/</guid>
      <description>(Vienna, VA February 21, 2023) The Sequoia Project, a non-profit and trusted advocate for nationwide health information exchange, launched the Consumer Voices Workgroup to understand first-hand from consumers the barriers they face accessing, using, and sharing their health information and to inform strategies to address the barriers. The non-profit, known for convening industry and government within its Interoperability Matters cooperative, is engaging consumers, patients, care partners and caregivers for the first time in its pursuit of nationwide seamless, secure health information sharing for better and more effective healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Expectations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/patient-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 16:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/patient-expectations/</guid>
      <description>The healthcare industry has significantly improved thanks to technology. What is on the horizon now that we have entered the world of information sharing? This week&amp;rsquo;s guest, Casey Quinlan, is a journalist, data rights activist, and the author of Amazons bestseller Cancer for Christmas: Making the Most of a Daunting Gift. Casey has a special interest in healthcare healthcare tech and has a big voice in the e-patient community. The World Health Organization tagged her as a patient engagement expert in 2014.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consumer Choice in U.S. Health Care: Using Insights from the Past to Inform the Way Forward</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/consumer-choice-in-u-s--health-care--using-insights-from-the-past-to-inform-the-way-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 15:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/consumer-choice-in-u-s--health-care--using-insights-from-the-past-to-inform-the-way-forward/</guid>
      <description>Consumer choice in health care has been advanced as a pathway for improving the quality and affordability of health care. The idea is that when people have access to full and accurate information about the quality and cost of health insurance plans, physicians, hospitals, and services and appropriate tools for using that information they will be able to choose the best options for themselves and their families.1Patients who have the information and incentives to act on the information, the thinking goes, will choose higher-priced options only if these offer higher quality and make them better off.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Need-to-Knows: The ABCs of HIEs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/patient-need-to-knows--the-abcs-of-hies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 10:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/patient-need-to-knows--the-abcs-of-hies/</guid>
      <description>Patient Need-to-Knows: The ABCs of HIEs&#xA;Enlightening Results, LLC&#xA;0/140 30.0 seconds&#xA;Cancel&#xA;Continue clipping after ad finishes&#xA;Cant create clip while ad is playing&#xA;Description Patient Need-to-Knows: The ABCs of HIEs&#xA;Medigy TV&#xA;Medigy TV&#xA;0 Likes&#xA;3 Views&#xA;Oct 3 2022&#xA;Comments 3 views Oct 3, 2022&#xA;3 views Oct 3, 2022&#xA;0DislikeShare&#xA;Download&#xA;Medigy TV&#xA;Medigy TV&#xA;5 subscribers&#xA;Subscribed Comments&#xA;Add a comment&amp;hellip;&#xA;All Listenable The Turning Point &amp;ndash; Surviving Sepsis coopertv</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Civitas Recap: Day One, We are #BetterTogether2022!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/2022-civitas-recap--day-one--we-are--bettertogether2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 01:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/2022-civitas-recap--day-one--we-are--bettertogether2022/</guid>
      <description>2022 Civitas Recap: Day One, We are #BetterTogether2022!Posted by Nathan Elliott on August 29, 2022Summaries by Nathan Elliott. Formatting and editing by Madeline RizzoOn DemandDay OneDay TwoDay ThreeCivitas Networks for Health is a national collaborative comprised of member organizations working to use health information exchange, health data, and multi-stakeholder, cross-sector approaches to improve health.Were in San Antonio this year for the Civitas Networks for Health 2022 Annual Conference. Join us over the upcoming days as we recap selected sessions from this years events!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Exchange and Medical Records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/data-exchange-and-medical-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 18:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/data-exchange-and-medical-records/</guid>
      <description>Patient Need to Know webinar: Dr. Steven Lane and Arien Malec&#xA;Read on youtube.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Its Time We Treat Medical Records Requests as a Critical Customer Service Issue with Grace Cordovano</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/it-s-time-we-treat-medical-records-requests-as-a-critical-customer-service-issue-with-grace-cordovano/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 06:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/it-s-time-we-treat-medical-records-requests-as-a-critical-customer-service-issue-with-grace-cordovano/</guid>
      <description>https://thehcbiz.com/197-medical-records-requests-as-critical-customer-service-issue-with-grace-cordovano/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Clinical Uses of Medical Records in Medically Complex Pediatrics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/non-clinical-uses-of-medical-records-in-medically-complex-pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 14:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/non-clinical-uses-of-medical-records-in-medically-complex-pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Patient Need to Know webinar: Erica Olenski Johansen&#xA;Read on youtube.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Power of Automation to Address the Information Blocking Rule and Empower Healthcare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/harnessing-the-power-of-automation-to-address-the-information-blocking-rule-and-empower-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 03:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/harnessing-the-power-of-automation-to-address-the-information-blocking-rule-and-empower-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMjpfq15oVI</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assisting patients dealing with an administrative burden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/assisting-patients-dealing-with-an-administrative-burden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 02:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/assisting-patients-dealing-with-an-administrative-burden/</guid>
      <description>The Unblock Health patient advocacy movement focuses on the administrative efforts patients face after a chronic illness or cancer diagnosis, according to Grace Cordovano, founder of Enlightening Results.&#xA;Read on healthcarefinancenews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI, ML, and NLP Snub Patients Right of Access</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/ai--ml--and-nlp-snub-patients--right-of-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 19:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/ai--ml--and-nlp-snub-patients--right-of-access/</guid>
      <description>Artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) are expected to transform healthcare. Clinical decision support (CDS) tools are expected to streamline physician workflows while intelligently personalizing patient care, decreasing physician burden, and enhancing patient care with precision and accuracy.However, patients currently do not have access to their own intelligent summaries or data outputs. While patients do not see documentation in their medical records if their physicians are utilizing CDS outputs to guide their care, they should be able to submit a medical record request to request a copy of the CDS outputs being used at the point of care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consumer and Patient Experience  Same or Different? </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/consumer-and-patient-experience---same-or-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 17:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/consumer-and-patient-experience---same-or-different/</guid>
      <description>The term consumer experience has become more prevalent in healthcare over the past couple of years. Many Health IT companies and organizations use the term interchangeably with patient experience. That is a mistake according to an expert panel at the 2022 HIMSS conference. The two are not the same. Patients Are Not Homogenous Day 1&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter mourns educator Dr. Nadia Chaudhri. What can be learned from her story?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/twitter-mourns-educator-dr--nadia-chaudhri--what-can-be-learned-from-her-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 17:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/twitter-mourns-educator-dr--nadia-chaudhri--what-can-be-learned-from-her-story/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen time and time againthe benefit that social media can have in connecting people, said patient advocate Grace Cordovano.Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a person living with a rare disease, who thinks that there&amp;rsquo;s no one in their community, in their county, in their state, in their country, to be able to connect with someone, perhaps even on the other side of the world, with the same diagnosis and start to forge a relationship, start gathering information and really learning on the fly, to try to get up to speed with this new diagnosis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual care enhances experience for chronically ill patients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/virtual-care-enhances-experience-for-chronically-ill-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 04:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/virtual-care-enhances-experience-for-chronically-ill-patients/</guid>
      <description>Patient advocate Grace Cordovano speaks about how telehealth and virtual care have improved outcomes and made it easier for chronically ill patients to live fuller, more satisfying lives.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning &amp; AI for Healthcare Forum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/machine-learning---ai-for-healthcare-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 22:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/machine-learning---ai-for-healthcare-forum/</guid>
      <description>The Patients Perspective on the Use of AI11:30 AM-11:55 AM ETDay 2 Morning SegmentGrace CordovanoFounder &amp;amp; Board-Certified Patient AdvocateEnlightening Results, LLCFrank CutittaChief Executive OfficerHealthTech Decision LabIts long been a lament of patients that doctors and clinicians spend too much time behind laptops or staring at screens. Natural language processing programs and others have come on to the scene to help alleviate this issue however some of these programs bring their own problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating the Patient Voice: Empathy Amplifier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/accelerating-the-patient-voice--empathy-amplifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/accelerating-the-patient-voice--empathy-amplifier/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of the Accelerate Health podcast, patient advocate and empathy amplifier Grace Cordovano discusses the importance of patient voice and empowerment in healthcare decisions.&#xA;Read on himss.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparency of Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning-enabled Medical Devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/transparency-of-artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-enabled-medical-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/transparency-of-artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-enabled-medical-devices/</guid>
      <description>FDA is announcing a virtual public workshop on transparency of Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning (AI/ML)-enabled medical devices to patients, caregivers, and providers. The role of transparency that enhances safe and effective use of AI/ML-enabled medical devices will be discussed, with an emphasis on information sharing methods such as labeling.&#xA;Read on fda.yorkcast.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Health Literacy  </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/the-impact-of-health-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 13:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/the-impact-of-health-literacy/</guid>
      <description>On this episode of HI Pitch, Grace Cordovano, PhD, BCPA, discusses the importance of health literacy and health education. Grace is a noted patient advocate and the founder of Unblock Health. You will be inspired after hearing Grace talk about health literacy and how health information can empower patients.&#xA;Read on hi-pitch-the-ahima-podcast.simplecast.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wide Variety of Topics at #AHIMA21 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/wide-variety-of-topics-at--ahima21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 14:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/wide-variety-of-topics-at--ahima21/</guid>
      <description>AHIMA Foundation, the charitable arm of AHIMA, is taking on health equity by focusing on the challenge of health literacy. At #AHIMA21 the Foundation announced the creation of a steering committee to support the organizations consumer-centered Health Literacy for Health Equity campaign and programming. The Committee will be instrumental in shaping the strategic direction of the upcoming consumer campaign, as well as driving the Foundations holistic vision to nurture a solutions-based, resource-dense hub for consumers, advocates and healthcare industry stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Experience Podcast - The Beryl Institute - Improving the Patient Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/patient-experience-podcast---the-beryl-institute---improving-the-patient-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 01:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/patient-experience-podcast---the-beryl-institute---improving-the-patient-experience/</guid>
      <description>Hacking Healthcare is the Only Way OutDr. Grace Cordovano is a board certified patient advocate with a wealth of experience navigating the US healthcare system on behalf of herself, family and clients. In this podcast, Dr. Cordovano helps us understand what she means by &amp;ldquo;hacking healthcare&amp;rdquo; in order to move from &amp;ldquo;patient-centered care&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;life-focused care.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Read on theberylinstitute.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Award Winner Pam Landis: Bringing Health IT, Communications &amp; Operations Together </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/award-winner-pam-landis--bringing-health-it--communications---operations-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 14:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/award-winner-pam-landis--bringing-health-it--communications---operations-together/</guid>
      <description>Pam Landis, Vice President of Digital Engagement at Hackensack Meridian Health lead her team through a series of successful projects last year, including standing up a COVID-19 vaccination scheduling system in just a few weeks. She had to be resourceful and resilient. Her work was recognized with the 2021 Medigy HITMC Award for Marketer of []&#xA;Read on hitmc.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips for Smoother Patient Access to Health Information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/5-tips-for-smoother-patient-access-to-health-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 17:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/5-tips-for-smoother-patient-access-to-health-information/</guid>
      <description>Guest blog contributor Grace Cordovano discusses insights and tips on helping patient access their health information.&#xA;Read on srhealth.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Pharma Research To Virtual First Strategies And State Policy Trends, ATA2021 Delivers Insights, Best Practices And Innovations To Catalyze Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/from-pharma-research-to-virtual-first-strategies-and-state-policy-trends--ata2021-delivers-insights--best-practices-and-innovations-to-catalyze-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 11:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/from-pharma-research-to-virtual-first-strategies-and-state-policy-trends--ata2021-delivers-insights--best-practices-and-innovations-to-catalyze-change/</guid>
      <description>WASHINGTON, DC, MAY 26, 2021 The American Telemedicine Associations 25th Annual Conference and Expo features a lineup of newsmakers, thought leaders and visionaries set to take the virtual stage at ATA2021. Some of the conference highlights include: Opening Keynote: Lessons Learned from 2020 Provide a Springboard for Increased Telehealth Adoption (June 1, 11:10-11:30am EST)more&#xA;Read on americantelemed.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Confidence in COVID-19 Vaccines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/building-confidence-in-covid-19-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 18:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/building-confidence-in-covid-19-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>It was my pleasure to be a panelist during a recent virtual forum titled Building Vaccine Confidence: Best Practices to Combat Misinformation and Vaccine Hesitancy in COVID-19 Vaccines. The forum&#xA;Read on directorsblog.nih.gov</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Connect With Patients in Post-Vaccine COVID World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/5-ways-to-connect-with-patients-in-post-vaccine-covid-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 12:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/5-ways-to-connect-with-patients-in-post-vaccine-covid-world/</guid>
      <description>Grace Cordovano shares five tips to help healthcare providers educate and prepare patients for the COVID-19 vaccine.&#xA;Read on srhealth.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First COVID19 Vaccine: What to Expect  Enlightening Results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/my-first-covid19-vaccine--what-to-expect---enlightening-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 16:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/my-first-covid19-vaccine--what-to-expect---enlightening-results/</guid>
      <description>My First COVID-19 Vaccine: What to Expect Last week I had the opportunity to do something surreal. I received my first dose of the COVID-19 vaccine. Heres a step-by-step look at my experience and what to expect. With my mask on, I walked through parking lot M of the Meadowlands Comple&#xA;Read on enlighteningresults.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 10 Patient and Carepartner Priorities You Must Pursue in 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/the-10-patient-and-carepartner-priorities-you-must-pursue-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 12:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/the-10-patient-and-carepartner-priorities-you-must-pursue-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>Grace Cordovano discusses 10 patient and carepartner priorities healthcare organizations should pursue in 2021.&#xA;Read on srhealth.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Digital Health Experience May Push Patients to Change Docs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/poor-digital-health-experience-may-push-patients-to-change-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 14:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/poor-digital-health-experience-may-push-patients-to-change-docs/</guid>
      <description>But despite those increases in patient engagement technology use, medical consumers are looking for more from their providers. Thirty-one percent of respondents said they dont think their medical providers have gone to great enough lengths to improve the patient medical billing process, and about half said they want healthcare to be more seamless.&#xA;Read on patientengagementhit.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Requesting Medical Records </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/requesting-medical-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 03:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/requesting-medical-records/</guid>
      <description>HIM professionals have the power to significantlyand directlyimpact the lives of patients and providers. The Cures Act offers a pivotal opportunity for HIM professionals to become agents of change for patients, shifting the profession from playing a role primarily focused on medical records to a champion for seamless, strategic health information access.&#xA;Read on journal.ahima.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating APIs in Healthcare: A Year in Review and Momentum for 2021 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/accelerating-apis-in-healthcare--a-year-in-review-and-momentum-for-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 22:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/accelerating-apis-in-healthcare--a-year-in-review-and-momentum-for-2021/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, December 1, 2020; 1:00 PM - 5:00 PM, Join us on December 1, 2020, as we spotlight how application programming interface (API)-forward policies and industry actions are accelerating interoperability. This event will include updates from federal agencies as well as presentations and demos from industry partners that highlight how work underway is advancing innovation and competition in the health IT ecosystem. A panel discussion will also be held at the end of the day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Can Patients Get Medical Records from a Closed Medical Practice?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/how-can-patients-get-medical-records-from-a-closed-medical-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 16:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/how-can-patients-get-medical-records-from-a-closed-medical-practice/</guid>
      <description>What should patients do when their doctors office closes, and they need a copy of their medical records? This is especially challenging when a doctor may not have had an EHR, as is the case with many independent practices as well as more rural settings. On September 26, 2020, a tweet from Cait DesRoches, Executive Director of OpenNotes, inquired about how a family member may get access to medical records from her physicans practice that closed, triggering a robust conversation that led to the realization that patients and families are not well informed in these circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THCB Gang, Episode 19, July 23, 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/thcb-gang--episode-19--july-23--2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/thcb-gang--episode-19--july-23--2020/</guid>
      <description>This episode of the THCB Gang included regulars Grace Cordavano (@GraceCordovano) , Deven McGraw (@HealthPrivacy), Ian Morrison (@seccurve), and special guest patient entrepreneur Robin Farmanfarmaian (@Robinff3). We talked about patient experiences, the state of play in health care business, and about new technologies and more. And after tomorrow it gets preserved as a podcast on Itunes &amp;amp; Spotify Enjoy!&#xA;Read on thehealthcareblog.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Health Care Blog&#39;s Podcasts: THCB Gang Episode 17: Patients and Technology, and the Supreme Court Ruiling on Birth Control on Apple Podcasts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/the-health-care-blog-s-podcasts--thcb-gang-episode-17--patients-and-technology--and-the-supreme-court-ruiling-on-birth-control-on-apple-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 18:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/the-health-care-blog-s-podcasts--thcb-gang-episode-17--patients-and-technology--and-the-supreme-court-ruiling-on-birth-control-on-apple-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Joining me were some of our regulars: patient advocate Grace Cordovano, health economist Jane Sarasohn-Kahn, WTF Health Host Jessica DaMassa, and guests: Tina Park, partner at Diagram &amp;amp; Shannon Brownlee, Senior VP at the Lown Institute. The conversation focused on asynchronous care, the gap between patients &amp;amp; technology, and the Supreme Court ruling on employers&amp;rsquo; ability to limit women&amp;rsquo;s access to birth control coverage. It was a great and engaging conversation with some of the top health care experts in the field.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#ATA2020: 4 Ways to Transform the Telehealth Patient Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/ata2020--4-ways-to-transform-the-telehealth-patient-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 03:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/ata2020--4-ways-to-transform-the-telehealth-patient-experience/</guid>
      <description>Some providers have spun up consumer-facing help desks to troubleshoot throughout the journey; those who dont will struggle. We need a new contact person wheres the digital Sherpa? said Grace Cordovano, a patient advocate and digital health consultant. Its not up to the doctor or the receptionist or the patients grandchild.&#xA;Read on healthtechmagazine.net</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare IoT Data at the Point of Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/healthcare-iot-data-at-the-point-of-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 15:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/healthcare-iot-data-at-the-point-of-care/</guid>
      <description>To better understand the answers to these questions and more about IoT in healthcare, we work with Dell Technologies and brought together this great panel of experts:Mitch Parker, CISO at IU Health (@mitchparkerciso)Grace Cordovano, PhD, BCPA, Founder, Enlightening Results &amp;amp; Co-Founder of Unblock Health (@GraceCordovano)Wendy Bohner, Global Solution Architect for Health &amp;amp; Life Sciences at Intel (@Wbohner)Steven Lazer, Dell Technologies (@lazer_epic)John Lynn, Founder and Chief Editor at Healthcare IT Today (@techguy)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THCB Gang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/thcb-gang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 19:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/thcb-gang/</guid>
      <description>Every Thursday at 1PM PT/4PM ET we will host a live show with the THCB Gang. The THCB Gang consists of 4-6 semi-regular guests drawn from THCB authors and other assorted old friends of mine, who will shoot the shit about health care business, politics, practice, and tech. It should be fun but serious and informative! It will also be preserved as a podcast on Itunes &amp;amp; Spotify Enjoy Matthew Holt</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telemedicine During COVID: How Not to Fail Out of the Gate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/telemedicine-during-covid--how-not-to-fail-out-of-the-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 17:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/telemedicine-during-covid--how-not-to-fail-out-of-the-gate/</guid>
      <description>Implementing telehealth is important during the COVID-19 crisis. Read this article to uncover tips to launching telehealth successfully.&#xA;Read on solutionreach.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Policy &amp; Regulatory Changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/policy---regulatory-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 02:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/policy---regulatory-changes/</guid>
      <description>A collaborative health conversation with two experts on policy and regulatory changes in the context of COVID-19&#xA;Read on medium.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health IRL: Policy &amp; Regulatory Changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/health-irl--policy---regulatory-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/health-irl--policy---regulatory-changes/</guid>
      <description>Washington and many states and local governments have responded to COVID-19 by changing regulations at an unprecedented pace. Join Grace Cordovano, PhD, BCPA and Matt Fisher as they discuss the implications for healthcare providers and businesses, and also for patients and caregivers.&#xA;Read on bigmarker.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patients &amp; Vulnerable Populations Pandemically Left in the Dark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/patients---vulnerable-populations-pandemically-left-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 17:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/patients---vulnerable-populations-pandemically-left-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>By GRACE CORDOVANO PhD, BCPA To be honest, the United States blew it on the mask front. From a public health, caregiver and patient safety, as well as community transmission standpoint, weContinue reading&amp;hellip;&#xA;Read on thehealthcareblog.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People with serious illness can teach us about living with Covid19 -</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/people-with-serious-illness-can-teach-us-about-living-with-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 03:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/people-with-serious-illness-can-teach-us-about-living-with-covid19/</guid>
      <description>Patient advocates have developed strong partnerships with the clinical and research communities. When the stakes for accessing reliable information are high, those with serious illnesses are particularly invested in disseminating trusted information. This doesnt mean we are immune to misinformation, but given our high risk for Covid-19 vulnerability, we recognize an added layer of diligence to follow our clinical partners in sharing trusted information. Grace Cordovano, an oncology patient advocate, displays the strength of partnership with patients and clinicians in this LinkedIn post, calling for resources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The THCB Gang Episode 2, Today at 1pm PT/4pm ET</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/the-thcb-gang-episode-2--today-at-1pm-pt-4pm-et/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 19:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/the-thcb-gang-episode-2--today-at-1pm-pt-4pm-et/</guid>
      <description>We are back today with our new live show The THCB Gang that will be preserved as a weekly podcast and available on our Itunes &amp;amp; Spotify channels. Each week 4-6 semi-regular guests drawn from THCB authors and other assorted old friends of mine will shoot the shit about health care business, politics, practice, and tech. It should be fun but serious and informative!To kick off this week, joining me Ill have Michael Millenson (@MLMillenson), Grace Cordovano (@GraceCordovano), Vince Kuraitis (@VinceKuraitis), Ian Morrison (@seccurve)!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patients, Tech, and Pandemics, Oh My!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/patients--tech--and-pandemics--oh-my/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 22:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/patients--tech--and-pandemics--oh-my/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the opportunities and challenges of technology for patients and how it affects their experience managing their care and living their lives. We will also consider the health inequities that go along with tech solutions as well, and considerations for how to co-design future health innovations. And we would be remiss if we didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about the current global health concerns and how vulnerable populations hear you when you say &amp;ldquo;only the high risk should worry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F068 The power of patients 4/4: What skills do you need as a patient? (Grace Cordovano)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/f068-the-power-of-patients-4-4--what-skills-do-you-need-as-a-patient---grace-cordovano/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 04:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/f068-the-power-of-patients-4-4--what-skills-do-you-need-as-a-patient---grace-cordovano/</guid>
      <description>Grace Cordovano is an expert healthcare navigating solutionist and award winning, board-certified patient advocate specializing in the oncology space. She is the founder of Enlightening Results and Unblock Health - a suite of services that finally provides patients and carepartners with a way to level the playing field and demand access to the critical information needed to make informed, engaged, and empowered decisions about their care. In this episode, she talks about challenges patients faces because of the complexity of the healthcare system in the US, she shares her view about the need of patients getting access to their data and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Patients Meet HIPAA: Addressing Common HIPAA Access Questions In Real Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/when-patients-meet-hipaa--addressing-common-hipaa-access-questions-in-real-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 20:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/when-patients-meet-hipaa--addressing-common-hipaa-access-questions-in-real-life/</guid>
      <description>As more patients are taking the drivers seat of their care, they encounter more and more frustrating HIPAA roadblocks and questions. Grace Cordovano, PhD, board-certified patient advocate, founder of Enlightening Results and co-founder of Unblock Health, frequently encounters the many facets of HIPAA as they relate to patients in real life. Here are some common scenarios presented by Dr. Cordovano that patients struggle with respect to HIPAA and what options may exist or how outcomes may be influenced.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Buzzwords That Should Be Retired in 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/healthcare-buzzwords-that-should-be-retired-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 13:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/healthcare-buzzwords-that-should-be-retired-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>From a patient and carepartner perspective, every stakeholder in the health care ecosystem claims they are putting the patient in the center of their care. Its crystal clear the vast majority of agents are profits over patients. In the new Roaring 20s, we demand partnership rooted in transparency, autonomy, inclusivity, and trust.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC 2020 - Balancing Patient Privacy with Data Access: Lessons from the Field</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/onc-2020---balancing-patient-privacy-with-data-access--lessons-from-the-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 19:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/onc-2020---balancing-patient-privacy-with-data-access--lessons-from-the-field/</guid>
      <description>Balancing Patient Privacy with Data Access: Lessons from the Field The use of secure, standards-based APIs will create new, exciting opportunities for patients and providers alike to share their data to improve their health. On this International #DataPrivacyDay, join a group of technologists, privacy experts, and patients for a robust discussion on balancing privacy with the expanding flow of health information.&#xA;No comments, be the first one to comment this video!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grace Cordovano </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/grace-cordovano/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 22:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/grace-cordovano/</guid>
      <description>Grace Cordovano is a rare breed! She is an official Patient Advocate supporting people in navigating the complex and confusing healthcare system after they have received a cancer diagnosis.&#xA;Read on hitlikeagirlpod.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Ms. Judy Faulkner &amp; Mr. Tommy Thompson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/a-letter-to-ms--judy-faulkner---mr--tommy-thompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/a-letter-to-ms--judy-faulkner---mr--tommy-thompson/</guid>
      <description>This is what information blocking looks like boots on the ground.These are the realities people face when they are living with life-altering, life-limiting, absolutely earth-shattering diagnoses.&#xA;Read on thehealthcareblog.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Unblock Health Co-Founder, Grace Cordovano</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/interview-with-unblock-health-co-founder--grace-cordovano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 12:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/interview-with-unblock-health-co-founder--grace-cordovano/</guid>
      <description>When I saw the announcement of Unblock Health by my friends and colleagues, Dr. Grace Cordovano, BCPA, and Shahid Shah, I knew I had to learn more and help them in their efforts to Unblock Health f&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIPAA Year in Review </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/hipaa-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 17:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/hipaa-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Another effort, Unblock Health, was also tarted to increase awareness around access and improve individual understanding (an issue touched upon in a Healthcare de Jure episode with Grace Cordovano from Enlightening Results). The confluence of these events suggests that pressure will continue to be exerted, which will pick up new dimensions when the pending information blocking rule is finalized.&#xA;Read on healthitanswers.net</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Patient Perspective: Vulnerability, Data Abuse, &amp; Business as Usual</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/the-patient-perspective--vulnerability--data-abuse----business-as-usual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 04:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/the-patient-perspective--vulnerability--data-abuse----business-as-usual/</guid>
      <description>In the wake of the report detailing the Ascension-Google, Project Nightingale, patients are left wondering what the consequences of this, and other similar tech giant partnerships, will be for their near and long-term future. Patients fear being discriminated against, suffering a reputation loss, the risk of losing employment opportunities, and being classified in a manner that makes insurance unaffordable or potentially inaccessible.&#xA;There are legitimate concerns about the commercialization of biased AI predictive decision-making algorithms that may negatively impact their care as has been recently reported.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare must meet patients where they are</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/healthcare-must-meet-patients-where-they-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 04:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/healthcare-must-meet-patients-where-they-are/</guid>
      <description>Patient autonomy is revolutionized by access to their data, says Grace Cordovano, board-certified patient advocate and CEO of Enlightening Results.&#xA;Read on himsstv.brightcovegallery.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s Got the Patient&#39;s Back? with Patient Advocate Grace Cordovano</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/press/who-s-got-the-patient-s-back--with-patient-advocate-grace-cordovano/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 10:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/press/who-s-got-the-patient-s-back--with-patient-advocate-grace-cordovano/</guid>
      <description>Grace Cordovanois a board-certified patient advocate. Grace helps us to understand why patient advocates are needed, how they add value, and how much work and expertise is really necessary to do this job effectively.&#xA;Read on thehcbiz.com</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
