<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STAT on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/stat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in STAT on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 17:10:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/stat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Bidens latest Cancer Moonshot efforts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-to-make-of-biden-s-latest-cancer-moonshot-efforts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 17:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-to-make-of-biden-s-latest-cancer-moonshot-efforts/</guid>
      <description>President Bidens latest Cancer Moonshot efforts are inspiring hope among cancer researchers, but not everyone is impressed.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misdiagnoses cost the U.S. 800,000 deaths and serious disabilities every year, study finds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/misdiagnoses-cost-the-u-s--800-000-deaths-and-serious-disabilities-every-year--study-finds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 16:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/misdiagnoses-cost-the-u-s--800-000-deaths-and-serious-disabilities-every-year--study-finds/</guid>
      <description>An estimated 371,000 people die every year following a misdiagnosis, and 424,000 are permanently disabled, researchers reported in a study published in BMJ.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As fear rises over AI, Google and Epic fight stronger regulation of the technology in health care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/as-fear-rises-over-ai--google-and-epic-fight-stronger-regulation-of-the-technology-in-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 21:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/as-fear-rises-over-ai--google-and-epic-fight-stronger-regulation-of-the-technology-in-health-care/</guid>
      <description>As fear rises over AI, Google, Epic, and other big companies are fighting stronger regulation of the technology in health care.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How UnitedHealth&#39;s acquisition of a popular Medicare Advantage algorithm sparked internal dissent over denied care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/how-unitedhealth-s-acquisition-of-a-popular-medicare-advantage-algorithm-sparked-internal-dissent-over-denied-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 16:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/how-unitedhealth-s-acquisition-of-a-popular-medicare-advantage-algorithm-sparked-internal-dissent-over-denied-care/</guid>
      <description>It was very much about following the algorithms and basically not using your clinical judgment, one former NaviHealth medical reviewer said. That was very different from before we were owned by Optum.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The high hopes  and high stakes  behind Microsoft and Epic&#39;s plan to use AI to answer patient questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/the-high-hopes---and-high-stakes---behind-microsoft-and-epic-s-plan-to-use-ai-to-answer-patient-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 14:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/the-high-hopes---and-high-stakes---behind-microsoft-and-epic-s-plan-to-use-ai-to-answer-patient-questions/</guid>
      <description>A pilot at three large health systems will use generative AI to help doctors respond to patients questions in online portals.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;We&#39;re getting much more aggressive&#39;: Microsoft&#39;s Nuance adds GPT-4 AI to its medical note-taking tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/we-re-getting-much-more-aggressive--microsoft-s-nuance-adds-gpt-4-ai-to-its-medical-note-taking-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 21:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/we-re-getting-much-more-aggressive--microsoft-s-nuance-adds-gpt-4-ai-to-its-medical-note-taking-tool/</guid>
      <description>The field is open for Nuance to really accelerate their product development and deployment and their market share.&amp;quot;&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimal compliance, or meaningful change? Epic faces a crossroads as new rules put pressure on health data sharing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/minimal-compliance--or-meaningful-change--epic-faces-a-crossroads-as-new-rules-put-pressure-on-health-data-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 02:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/minimal-compliance--or-meaningful-change--epic-faces-a-crossroads-as-new-rules-put-pressure-on-health-data-sharing/</guid>
      <description>Epics practices have made it harder for physicians to practice and has proven to be a consistent roadblock to true interoperability across the healthcare industry, said Glen Tullman, a former CEO of Epic competitor AllScripts and current CEO of Transcarent, a startup seeking to simplify health insurance benefits. Everyone knows this, but few want to acknowledge it publicly.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internal documents show privacy lapses at a data powerhouse that holds health records and consumer information on millions of Americans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/internal-documents-show-privacy-lapses-at-a-data-powerhouse-that-holds-health-records-and-consumer-information-on-millions-of-americans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 16:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/internal-documents-show-privacy-lapses-at-a-data-powerhouse-that-holds-health-records-and-consumer-information-on-millions-of-americans/</guid>
      <description>Individual harms may arise if drugs get overprescribed, prove less effective than advertised, or cause patients to pay more for a certain product even when a cheaper alternative is available because of a relationship between a doctor and drugmaker they dont know about.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A troubling report on Cerner&#39;s VA rollout offers a rare look into the hidden harms of health records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/a-troubling-report-on-cerner-s-va-rollout-offers-a-rare-look-into-the-hidden-harms-of-health-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 03:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/a-troubling-report-on-cerner-s-va-rollout-offers-a-rare-look-into-the-hidden-harms-of-health-records/</guid>
      <description>According to the results of an inspection released this month by the VAs Office of Inspector General, more than 11,000 requests for clinical orders in the new Oracle-Cerner EHR at one medical center ended up in a digital no-mans land called the unknown queue. Those overlooked orders resulted in 149 cases of patient harm two that were especially severe. In one case, the system obscured a referral for follow-up psychiatric care for a patient at risk of suicide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Court&#39;s decision on abortion sparks health tech&#39;s Cambridge Analytica moment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/supreme-court-s-decision-on-abortion-sparks-health-tech-s-cambridge-analytica-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 23:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/supreme-court-s-decision-on-abortion-sparks-health-tech-s-cambridge-analytica-moment/</guid>
      <description>The wild west of health data has led to numerous smaller-scale scandals over the years: Googles effort to build up its health care business with millions of patient records from Ascension drew criticism. Flo, which makes a period-tracking app once again in the spotlight, settled with the Federal Trade Commision last year over allegations it misled users about the privacy of their data. And just weeks ago, an investigation revealed major hospital systems were sending health information to Facebook, which experts said could be in violation of HIPAA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A national patient ID is essential for patient safety</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/a-national-patient-id-is-essential-for-patient-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 03:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/a-national-patient-id-is-essential-for-patient-safety/</guid>
      <description>A national strategy for patient identification is essential for connecting the fragmented health care system, while making it safer and more efficient for patients and health providers.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a complex web of businesses turned private health records from GE into a lucrative portrait of patients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/how-a-complex-web-of-businesses-turned-private-health-records-from-ge-into-a-lucrative-portrait-of-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/how-a-complex-web-of-businesses-turned-private-health-records-from-ge-into-a-lucrative-portrait-of-patients/</guid>
      <description>But privacy experts said it shouldnt be up to IQVIA, or any other for-profit company, to decide how patients personal information is used. Who are you to decide what benefits these people? Yasnoff said. What gives you the right to be judge, jury, and executioner?To Yasnoff, the common comparison of medical data to oil a commodity to be freely traded entirely misunderstands the unique nature of data. Oil gets burned and cant be reused, but information can be reused, and so is very valuable, he said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top privacy researchers urge the health care industry to safeguard patient data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/top-privacy-researchers-urge-the-health-care-industry-to-safeguard-patient-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 12:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/top-privacy-researchers-urge-the-health-care-industry-to-safeguard-patient-data/</guid>
      <description>This market in medical records has become highly lucrative $13.5 billion annually thanks to advances in artificial intelligence that enable the slicing, dicing, and cross-referencing of that data in powerful new ways.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a decades-old database became a hugely profitable dossier on the health of 270 million Americans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/how-a-decades-old-database-became-a-hugely-profitable-dossier-on-the-health-of-270-million-americans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 11:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/how-a-decades-old-database-became-a-hugely-profitable-dossier-on-the-health-of-270-million-americans/</guid>
      <description>As a repository of sensitive patient information, the companys databases churn silently behind the scenes of their medical care, scooping up their most guarded secrets: the diseases they have, the drugs theyre taking, the places their bodies are broken that they havent told anyone but their doctor. The family of databases that make up MarketScan now include the records of a stunning 270 million Americans, or 82% of the population.The vast reach of MarketScan, and its immense value, is unmistakable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clinicians open their notes to patients in grand experiment in medical care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/clinicians-open-their-notes-to-patients-in-grand-experiment-in-medical-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 15:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/clinicians-open-their-notes-to-patients-in-grand-experiment-in-medical-care/</guid>
      <description>Whatevers put there is going to follow you for life, Thomas said. I think its important that patients understand that now. She appreciates being able to see what providers are writing about her and her illness so that she can advocate for herself. As doctors learn how to make their comments clearer, Thomas thinks open notes will help other patients become stronger advocates for themselves.&#xA;Read on statnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It shouldn&#39;t take medical training to help a loved one get great care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/it-shouldn-t-take-medical-training-to-help-a-loved-one-get-great-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 12:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/it-shouldn-t-take-medical-training-to-help-a-loved-one-get-great-care/</guid>
      <description>I also spent hours coordinating between his cancer doctors and the team taking care of him in the hospital. I requested that his records descriptions of his surgery and pathology reports be sent to his cancer team. When their opinions contradicted those of the physicians on site, I helped my dad make his own informed decisions. I repeatedly reminded him that his care is his choice, even though it often feels like doctors call the shots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teladoc Health reaches agreement to buy Livongo in a $18.5 billion deal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/teladoc-health-reaches-agreement-to-buy-livongo-in-a--18-5-billion-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 18:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/teladoc-health-reaches-agreement-to-buy-livongo-in-a--18-5-billion-deal/</guid>
      <description>Telemedicine provider Teladoc Health has reached an agreement to buy the diabetes coaching company Livongo in an $18.5 billion deal that will create the first true health tech giant in an era in which demand for virtual care is surging.The merger agreement, announced on Wednesday morning, is expected to create a combined company on track to bring in $1.3 billion in revenue this year, up 85% over last year. Jason Gorevic, Teladocs current CEO, will be the CEO of the newly combined company, which will be called Teladoc and will be based in New York.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health data privacy draws fresh scrutiny from lawmakers amid pandemic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/health-data-privacy-draws-fresh-scrutiny-from-lawmakers-amid-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 01:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/health-data-privacy-draws-fresh-scrutiny-from-lawmakers-amid-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>All three bills focus on the type of health data that falls outside the scope of the federal privacy law known as HIPAA, which only applies to entities like hospitals and clinics and their business associates. The architects of the law, first passed in 1996 and amended slightly over the years, could not have imagined the current reality in which public health agencies are developing apps to track coronavirus patients and their contacts using technology built by Google and Apple.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
