<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HHS.gov on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/hhs.gov/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HHS.gov on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 21:53:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/hhs.gov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HHS Open Data and InnovationX for Impact at the 2023 Health Datap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/hhs-open-data-and-innovationx-for-impact-at-the-2023-health-datap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 21:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/hhs-open-data-and-innovationx-for-impact-at-the-2023-health-datap/</guid>
      <description>2023 Health Datapalooza accelerates momentum for HHS CancerX, Startup Days &amp;amp; the launch of Health Equity DataJam to transform HHS open data into tools &amp;amp; action.&#xA;Read on hhs.gov</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIPAA Privacy Rule and Disclosures of Information Relating to Reproductive Health Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/hipaa-privacy-rule-and-disclosures-of-information-relating-to-reproductive-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 14:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/hipaa-privacy-rule-and-disclosures-of-information-relating-to-reproductive-health-care/</guid>
      <description>The Office for Civil Rights (OCR) administers and enforces the Privacy Rule, which establishes requirements with respect to the use, disclosure, and protection of PHI by covered entities (health plans, health care clearinghouses, and most health care providers)4 and, to some extent, by their business associates.5 These regulated entities can use or disclose PHI, without an individuals signed authorization,6 only as expressly permitted or required by the Privacy Rule.7 ,8The Privacy Rule permissions for disclosing PHI without an individuals authorization for purposes not related to health care, such as disclosures to law enforcement officials, are narrowly tailored to protect the individuals privacy and support their access to health services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting the Privacy and Security of Your Health Information When Using Your Personal Cell Phone or Tablet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/protecting-the-privacy-and-security-of-your-health-information-when-using-your-personal-cell-phone-or-tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 14:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/protecting-the-privacy-and-security-of-your-health-information-when-using-your-personal-cell-phone-or-tablet/</guid>
      <description>The HIPAA Rules generally do not protect the privacy or security of your health information when it is accessed through or stored on your personal cell phones or tablets. The HIPAA Rules apply only when PHI is created, received, maintained, or transmitted by covered entities and business associates. For example, the HIPAA Rules do not protect the privacy of your Internet search history, information you voluntarily share online, or your geographic location information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methods for De-identification of PHI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/methods-for-de-identification-of-phi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/methods-for-de-identification-of-phi/</guid>
      <description>This page provides guidance about methods and approaches to achieve de-identification in accordance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) Privacy Rule. The guidance explains and answers questions regarding the two methods that can be used to satisfy the Privacy Rules de-identification standard: Expert Determination and Safe Harbor .This guidance is intended to assist covered entities to understand what is de-identification, the general process by which de-identified information is created, and the options available for performing de-identification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCR Resolves Twentieth Investigation in HIPAA Right of Access Initiative with $80,000 Settlement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-resolves-twentieth-investigation-in-hipaa-right-of-access-initiative-with--80-000-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 17:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-resolves-twentieth-investigation-in-hipaa-right-of-access-initiative-with--80-000-settlement/</guid>
      <description>The Office for Civil Rights (OCR) at the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services announces the resolution of its twentieth investigation in its HIPAA Right&#xA;Read on hhs.gov</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Help in Other Languages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/get-help-in-other-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 21:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/get-help-in-other-languages/</guid>
      <description>The Office for Civil Rights is here to help you understand your civil rights and right to the privacy of your health information in a variety of languages.&#xA;Read on hhs.gov</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCR Settles Ninth Investigation in HIPAA Right of Access Initiative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-settles-ninth-investigation-in-hipaa-right-of-access-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 16:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-settles-ninth-investigation-in-hipaa-right-of-access-initiative/</guid>
      <description>The Office for Civil Rights (OCR) at the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) announces that it has settled its ninth enforcement action in its HIPAA Right of Access Initiative. OCR announced this initiative as an enforcement priority in 2019 to support individuals&amp;rsquo; right to timely access to their health records at a reasonable cost under the HIPAA Privacy Rule.NY Spine Medicine (NY Spine) has agreed to take corrective actions and pay $100,000 to settle a potential violation of the HIPAA Privacy Rule&amp;rsquo;s right of access standard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCR Resolves Civil Rights Complaint Against Pennsylvania After it Revises its Pandemic Health Care Triaging Policies to Protect Against Disability Discrimination</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-resolves-civil-rights-complaint-against-pennsylvania-after-it-revises-its-pandemic-health-care-triaging-policies-to-protect-against-disability-discrimination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 03:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-resolves-civil-rights-complaint-against-pennsylvania-after-it-revises-its-pandemic-health-care-triaging-policies-to-protect-against-disability-discrimination/</guid>
      <description>OCR has reviewed the complaint and determined that, as a recipient of HHS funds, Pennsylvania is required to comply with the civil rights statutes listed above. OCR has been in communication with PDH, which has agreed to accept technical assistance from OCR and has revised its CSC Guidelines by:removing criteria that automatically deprioritized persons on the basis of particular disabilities,requiring individualized assessments based on the best available, relevant, and objective medical evidence to support triaging decisions, andensuring that no one is denied care based on stereotypes, assessments of quality of life, or judgments about a persons worth based on the presence or absence of disabilities.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
