<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2023-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2023-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Thursday December 14, 2023 and Friday December 15, 2023, Registration and Agenda to come this summerSign Up for Annual Meeting and Other ONC Updates</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NODE.Health&#39;s 7th Annual Digital Medicine Conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/node-health-s-7th-annual-digital-medicine-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 18:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/node-health-s-7th-annual-digital-medicine-conference/</guid>
      <description>At NODE.Health, we believe that evidence is the key to transforming innovative digital health concepts into viable, real-world digital medicine. Thats why, each year, we assemble thought leaders from across the continuumnot just to talk about digital health, but to collaborate on strategies and best practices for implementing evidence.&#xA;Read on digitalmedicineconference.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home SABCS 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/home-sabcs-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 17:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/home-sabcs-2023/</guid>
      <description>The San Antonio Breast Cancer Symposium (SABCS) is an annual event cosponsored by the AACR and UT Health San Antonios Mays Cancer Center. Now in its 46th year, the meeting hosts about 10,000 clinicians and scientists from all over the world and is the largest and most prestigious scientific gathering on breast cancer research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sequoia Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/the-sequoia-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/the-sequoia-project/</guid>
      <description>We are the independent, trusted advocate for nationwide health information exchange.&#xA;Read on sequoiaproject.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMIA 2023 Annual Symposium Registration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/amia-2023-annual-symposium-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 12:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/amia-2023-annual-symposium-registration/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open&#xA;Read on amia.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home - CNS Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/home---cns-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 17:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/home---cns-summit/</guid>
      <description>WHERE LIFE SCIENCES LEADERS GAIN YEAR-ROUND ACCESS TO THE NETWORKING AND KNOWLEDGE THEY NEED TO SUCCEED&#xA;Read on cnssummit.org </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home - Future of Cancer Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/home---future-of-cancer-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 16:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/home---future-of-cancer-care/</guid>
      <description>The Future of Cancer Care Summit is built in collaboration with CancerX; a public-private partnership announced by The White House as a national accelerator to boost innovation in the fight against cancer as part of the reignited Cancer Moonshot.&#xA;Co-hosted by Moffitt Cancer Center and the Digital Medicine Society (DiMe) alongside almost 100 founding members, the CancerX program convenes the many diverse stakeholders needed to unleash&#xA;Read on futurecancercare.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Patient Access to Health Data for Actionable Results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/enabling-patient-access-to-health-data-for-actionable-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 02:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/enabling-patient-access-to-health-data-for-actionable-results/</guid>
      <description>WEDNESDAY OCTOBER 18, 2023 FROM 12:00 5:00 PM ET, Recent Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) policy is bringing patients unprecedented access to their health information. Join the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) and Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) in Octoberfor avirtualevent focused on patient access to health data. The day will bring together patients, providers, payers, and health IT developers to discuss how HHS policies are working in practice and how to maximize the impact of these policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the State of Healthcare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/exploring-the-state-of-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 23:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/exploring-the-state-of-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the buzzwords of AI, genomics and ambient voice technology, let&amp;rsquo;s delve into the heart of the matter.&#xA;Read on eventbrite.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HLTH 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/hlth-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 16:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/hlth-2023/</guid>
      <description>HLTH 2023 is all about personalized experiences that focus on your goals. Join the 10,000+ anticipated attendees (including 2,500+ CEOs), 300+ Speakers, and 900+ Sponsors, all convening at HLTH 2023 to be part of healthcare&amp;rsquo;s preeminent all-inclusive event experience.&#xA;Read on hlth.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ECHAlliance Global Health Connector Event @ UNGA78 - ECHAlliance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/the-echalliance-global-health-connector-event---unga78---echalliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 18:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/the-echalliance-global-health-connector-event---unga78---echalliance/</guid>
      <description>Key Event Register Now Key Event Topics Healthy aging Data &amp;amp; Digital Green Health Key Event Read more key event Registration is now open Step 1 Sign up or login to register for the Science Summit @ UNGA here step 2 Follow this link where you will find all of our sessions. Here you can []&#xA;Read on echalliance.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>forum.defcon.org</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/forum-defcon-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 22:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/forum-defcon-org/</guid>
      <description>A community for Hackers, Researchers, DEF CON Groups, and anyone looking to explore the world of security.&#xA;Read on forum.defcon.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: Unpacking the State of Patient Privacy: A Survey of American Consumers. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--unpacking-the-state-of-patient-privacy--a-survey-of-american-consumers--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 11:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--unpacking-the-state-of-patient-privacy--a-survey-of-american-consumers--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>On July 11th, Health Gorilla released its State of Patient Privacy report (healthgorilla.com/home/patientprivacy), which surveyed over 1,200 patients about their attitudes towards health information sharing. In this webinar, we convene a distinguished panel of health data interoperability and privacy experts to discuss the findings live and share their perspectives. The panel will dive deep into patients&amp;rsquo; concerns with health data exchange, security and privacy of health data, and the benefits and risks of sharing data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HealthIMPACT Forum: Scalability, Security, and Smart Automation in Healthcare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/healthimpact-forum--scalability--security--and-smart-automation-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 12:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/healthimpact-forum--scalability--security--and-smart-automation-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>HealthlMPACT is a knowledge-sharing network that connects healthcare executives with the goal of improving patient experience, clinical outcomes, and operational efficiency through technology. We bring together healthcare executives ready to translate innovation into measurable and meaningful improvements in patient experience, clinical outcomes, and operational efficiency. We are delighted to be hosting HealthIMPACT in New York City and to be partnered with Amazon, the Sharp Index, NODEHealth, and MedStartr for two days focused on Scalability, Security, and Smart Automation in Healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HL7 FHIR DEVDAYS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/hl7-fhir-devdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 19:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/hl7-fhir-devdays/</guid>
      <description>Join us for the hybrid event of HL7 FHIR DevDays, which will be held in Amsterdam (the Netherlands), and/or through your screens!&#xA;Do you need FHIR in your day-to-day job?&#xA;DevDays is where you can learn all about FHIR and sharpen your FHIR expertise. DevDays is where the FHIR community lives and thrives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of AI and Personalized Cancer Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/the-future-of-ai-and-personalized-cancer-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/the-future-of-ai-and-personalized-cancer-care/</guid>
      <description>Join us!&#xA;Read on surveymonkey.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary - Digital Health Transformation Summit 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/summary---digital-health-transformation-summit-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 19:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/summary---digital-health-transformation-summit-2023/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Health Transformation Summit features an engaging lineup of educational content, with keynote presentations, interactive sessions and panel discussions curated by Modern Healthcare, as well as numerous opportunities to network and collaborate throughout the three-day event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IHA Health Literacy Conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/iha-health-literacy-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 21:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/iha-health-literacy-conference/</guid>
      <description>Come to IHAs 22nd Annual Health Literacy Conference to find out! Well explore how working together and using health literacy best practices can improve health equity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIMSS Global Health Conference &amp; Exhibition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/himss-global-health-conference---exhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/himss-global-health-conference---exhibition/</guid>
      <description>HIMSS23 is the cant-miss health information and technology event of the year, where professionals connect for education, innovation and collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViVE 2023 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/vive-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 18:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/vive-2023/</guid>
      <description>#ViVE2023ViVE is Back!Join the industry&amp;rsquo;s curated event experience for senior digital health leaders focusing on the business of healthcare systems.March 26-29, 2023 | Nashville, TN | Music City Center&#xA;Read on viveevent.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attend the SXSW Conference &amp; Festivals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/attend-the-sxsw-conference---festivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 04:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/attend-the-sxsw-conference---festivals/</guid>
      <description>The SXSW Conference &amp;amp; Festivals celebrate the convergence of the tech, film, and music industries. Located deep in the heart of Austin, Texas and online, SXSW is the premier destination for discovery.&#xA;Read on sxsw.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X4 - The Experience Management Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/x4---the-experience-management-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 05:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/x4---the-experience-management-summit/</guid>
      <description>The annual gathering of experience leaders is back. Live in Salt Lake City March 7-9, 2023. Where the visionaries and leaders behind the worlds most iconic brands will come together to share the stories behind the experiences delivering breakthrough business results.&#xA;Read on qualtrics.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Health Datapalooza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2023-health-datapalooza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 05:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2023-health-datapalooza/</guid>
      <description>AcademyHealth will once again host Health Datapalooza as a standalone conference in 2023. Unique among other data or health policy offerings, this event embodies the ethos of Datapaloozas beginnings with a renewed focus on the partnership between the public and private sectors to collaborate, innovate, and disrupt the industry. Join us February 23-24, 2023 in Arlington, VA for one of our most exciting meetings. Great minds across multiple sectors will convene and learn from each other to leverage data and policy for action that transforms health and health care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare and IT Marketing &amp; PR Conference - #HITMC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-and-it-marketing---pr-conference----hitmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 13:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-and-it-marketing---pr-conference----hitmc/</guid>
      <description>The first of its kind marketing &amp;amp; PR event focused solely on healthcare B2B marketing and PR.&#xA;Read on healthitmarketingconference.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequoia Project Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/sequoia-project-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 04:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/sequoia-project-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Sequoia ProjectAnnual Meeting&#xA;Read on sequoiaproject.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annual Digital Medicine Conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/annual-digital-medicine-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/annual-digital-medicine-conference/</guid>
      <description>6th AnnualDigital Medicine ConferenceDecember 7-8, 2022Microsoft, New YorkCome join thought-leaders in this one-of-a-kind event dedicated to bringing the promise of digital innovation to the real world of healthcare delivery.&#xA;Read on nodehealth.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HLTH 2022 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/hlth-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 18:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/hlth-2022/</guid>
      <description>HLTH is turning 5! Join our reimagined must-attend event that will continue to build upon our commitment to transforming the next 10 years of healthcare.The entire healthcare ecosystem will be there.&#xA;Read on hlth.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMIA 2022 Annual Symposium</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/amia-2022-annual-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/amia-2022-annual-symposium/</guid>
      <description>The Annual Symposium builds on more than 45 years of sharing research and insights for leveraging health information and cutting-edge technologies to improve human health. Scientific evidence is the language of trust in healthcare, and this years theme is Informatics: Building the Evidence Base.Among many other things, 2020 made us aware of the value of our community a community that we have missed: colleagues, mentors, experts, and students with a shared interest in informatics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Healthy Communities: Global Perspectives on Equity and Digital Health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/supporting-healthy-communities--global-perspectives-on-equity-and-digital-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 18:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/supporting-healthy-communities--global-perspectives-on-equity-and-digital-health/</guid>
      <description>Supporting Healthy Communities: Global Perspectives on Equity and Digital HealthNavigating the health system is often complex. As we take a deeper dive into health equity, this panel of experts will discuss the digital health and equity challenges that exist across our public health and health care systems that are driving public policy discussions globally. The panel will feature diverse perspectives from the US government, an Israeli health system, a federally qualified health center (FQHC), a patient and a patient advocate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: ONC Ask Us About Information Sharing. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--onc-ask-us-about-information-sharing--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 20:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--onc-ask-us-about-information-sharing--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>ONC Ask Us About Information Sharing&#xA;Read on kauffmaninc.zoom.us</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Health Equity Week</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/global-health-equity-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 02:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/global-health-equity-week/</guid>
      <description>Since 2006, U.S. National Health IT Week has brought together stakeholders in Washington, DC and across the country to demonstrate the power of information and technology to transform health. Today, HIMSS is pleased to use the power of this partner-driven platform to present Global Health Equity Week.HIMSS and the health information and technology community highlighted the role of digital health as a bridge to patient wellness by focusing on maternal health, patient identification and safety, telehealth, broadband access and public health data modernization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: ONC&#39;s Ask Us About Information Sharing. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--onc-s-ask-us-about-information-sharing--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 20:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--onc-s-ask-us-about-information-sharing--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>ONC&amp;rsquo;s Ask Us About Information Sharing&#xA;Read on kauffmaninc.zoom.us</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC Webinar: Countdown to Compliance  Information Blocking - Healthcare IT - CHIME</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-webinar--countdown-to-compliance---information-blocking---healthcare-it---chime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 21:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-webinar--countdown-to-compliance---information-blocking---healthcare-it---chime/</guid>
      <description>With a three week countdown to the information blocking compliance deadline, join us for a webinar with special guest Elise Sweeney Anthony J.D., from ONC. We will be discussing what healthcare providers need to know for October 6 and beyond, as well as common misconceptions and misunderstandings regarding compliance.&#xA;Read on chimecentral.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Surveillance and Data Security Public Forum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/commercial-surveillance-and-data-security-public-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/commercial-surveillance-and-data-security-public-forum/</guid>
      <description>The Commission is hosting a public forum regarding its Advanced Notice of Proposed Rulemaking(ANPR) on commercial surveillance and data security practices that harm consumers and competition. The public forum will include panel discussions and the public is invited to provide remarks.This is a virtual event.During the last portion of the public forum, members of the public are invited to share feedback on the FTCs Commercial Surveillance and Data Security Advanced Notice of Proposed Rulemaking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Annual Conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2022-annual-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 18:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2022-annual-conference/</guid>
      <description>Join us for The Civitas Networks for Health 2022 Annual Conference, a Collaboration with the DirectTrust Summit! Learn more here.&#xA;Read on civitasforhealth.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webinar Registration - Zoom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/webinar-registration---zoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 13:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/webinar-registration---zoom/</guid>
      <description>Inferno Framework Lets Build Description Come join the Inferno Team for a Lets Build session in the new Inferno Framework (https://inferno-framework.github.io/inferno-core/). In this session, youll learn how to leverage the Inferno Framework for standards conformance testing by developing tests for your own use cases, like HL7 FHIR implementation Guide conformance testing. These sessions will walk you through developing tests using the Inferno Framework, including basic and advanced features supported by Inferno.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Conferencing, Web Conferencing, Webinars, Screen Sharing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/video-conferencing--web-conferencing--webinars--screen-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 15:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/video-conferencing--web-conferencing--webinars--screen-sharing/</guid>
      <description>Its December 2023 Do you know where your data are? The definitive guide to ePHI, EHI Export and Designated Record SetsDescriptionAt the conclusion of the webinar, attendees will be able to:Describe the overlap and differences among ePHI, EHI Export, and DRS.Tie the definitions of ePHI, EHI Export and DRS to sections of the 21st Century Cures Act and the derived Code of Federal Regulations.Enumerate which data from which of the many IT systems each health system operates must be delivered on request.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registration  DevDays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/registration---devdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 19:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/registration---devdays/</guid>
      <description>HL7 FHIR DEVDAYS INTERNATIONAL June 6-9, 2022&#xA;Cleveland, OH | Hybrid Edition&#xA;Registration Registration for the 2022 international edition of HL7 FHIR DevDays is now open.&#xA;Registration Fees HL7 FHIR DevDays International Category&#xA;In person&#xA;In person&#xA;Virtual&#xA;Virtual&#xA;**Early Registration&#xA;**(paid by May 6, 2022)&#xA;Late Registration&#xA;_ (paid after May 6, 2022)_&#xA;Early Registration&#xA;(paid by May 6, 2022)&#xA;Late Registration&#xA;_ (paid after May 6, 2022)_</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 ONC Annual Meeting </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2022-onc-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 12:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2022-onc-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>February 2-3 and April 13-14, Updated ONC Annual Meeting ScheduleIn light of the current COVID-19 surge and the challenge it is creating for many, were making some adjustments to our Annual Meeting format for 2022.February 2-3, 2022: Education Sessions and Office Hours:Learn about Information Sharing, USCDI, and more!April 13-14, 2022: Panel Sessions, Exhibit Hall, and Networking:Join us for dynamic and engaging conversations about health IT and health equity, public health, patient access and advocacy, and health information exchange.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Health Datapalooza and National Health Policy Conference </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2022-health-datapalooza-and-national-health-policy-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 13:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2022-health-datapalooza-and-national-health-policy-conference/</guid>
      <description>n-person or online, the Health Datapalooza and National Health Policy Conference has an option for you.We know our audience misses the sense of community that comes with connecting, learning, and networking in-person, and that some aren&amp;rsquo;t yet ready to engage facemask-to-facemask. With that in mind, we are offering both in-person and online experiences this year.The annual co-located Health Datapalooza (HDP) and National Health Policy Conference (NHPC) will be offered in-person April 4-5 in Arlington, VA as a vaccine-required event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIMSS 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/himss-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 13:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/himss-22/</guid>
      <description>The HIMSS Global Health Conference &amp;amp; Exhibition is the cant-miss healthcare event of the year. Join us at HIMSS22 on March 1418, 2022 in person in Orlando, digitally or both.&#xA;Read on himss.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViVE 2022 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/vive-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 13:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/vive-2022/</guid>
      <description>Ready to Transform Healthcare?Were bringing together C-suite executives, senior digital health leaders and buyers, health startups and investors, government and solution providers to advance healthcare.Join us for four days in Miami Beach to discover what the best minds in healthcare can create together.&#xA;Read on viveevent.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 17:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/registration/</guid>
      <description>The Recognized Coordinating Entity (RCE) will share an in-depth review of specific aspects of the final Qualified Health Information Network Technical Framework (QTF) published on January 18, 2022. Anticipated topics for discussion include an overview of the framework as well the roadmap to incorporate FHIR-based exchange into TEFCA. This meeting will also provide interested stakeholders, including prospective Qualified Health Information Networks (QHINs), an opportunity to share their support, concerns, and ideas as the Common Agreement is implemented in 2022.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An ONC Artificial Intelligence Showcase  Seizing the Opportunities and Managing the Risks of Use of AI in Health IT </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/an-onc-artificial-intelligence-showcase---seizing-the-opportunities-and-managing-the-risks-of-use-of-ai-in-health-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 12:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/an-onc-artificial-intelligence-showcase---seizing-the-opportunities-and-managing-the-risks-of-use-of-ai-in-health-it/</guid>
      <description>January 14, 2022 from 1:00 pm to 4:30 pm ET, An ONC Artificial Intelligence Showcase Seizing the Opportunitiesand Managing the Risks of Use of AIin Health ITJoin us on January14, 2022from 1:00 pm to 4:30 pm ET, as we spotlight how federal agencies and industry partners are championing the design, development, and deployment of responsible, trustworthy AIinhealth IT.Watchupdates from federal agencies working to support AI innovation, while attempting to mitigate the risks of AIin health care, including its potential for unethical use and exacerbating systemic biases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WEBINAR: What Health Healthcare Providers Need to Know About Information Sharing &amp;amp; the Information Blocking Regulation (Webinar #2) </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/webinar--what-health-healthcare-providers-need-to-know-about-information-sharing--amp--the-information-blocking-regulation--webinar--2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/webinar--what-health-healthcare-providers-need-to-know-about-information-sharing--amp--the-information-blocking-regulation--webinar--2/</guid>
      <description>November 17, 2021 at 1:30PM ET, Join us onNovember 17, 2021from 1:30 pm to 2:30 pmESTfor thenextwebinar in ONCs clinician-focused webinar series on information sharing and the information blocking regulation. ONC experts will explain how ONC supports secure, appropriate sharing of electronic health information and how information sharing leads to more affordable and equitable care and improved care quality.Hear answers to questions such as:What is electronic health information (EHI)?Why does information sharing matter and how does it empower health care providers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HealthIMPACT Live Fall Forum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/healthimpact-live-fall-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/healthimpact-live-fall-forum/</guid>
      <description>Since July 2020 HealthIMPACT has hosted over 100 conversations on how to leverage technology to build a better, stronger, and more equitable healthcare system.&#xA;Read on healthimpactfall.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRI Virtual Immunotherapy Patient Summit  Cancer Research Institute (CRI)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/cri-virtual-immunotherapy-patient-summit---cancer-research-institute--cri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 18:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/cri-virtual-immunotherapy-patient-summit---cancer-research-institute--cri/</guid>
      <description>Free. Online. October 7-8, 2021. Join cancer patients and caregivers to learn about new breakthroughs in immunotherapy from leading physician-scientists.&#xA;Read on summit.cancerresearch.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 ONC Tech Forum Virtual   </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2021-onc-tech-forum-virtual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 17:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2021-onc-tech-forum-virtual/</guid>
      <description>September 10 and September 17, 2021, Register today for the all-virtual 2021 ONC Tech Forum to hear industry perspectives on the progress made in health IT over the past year, and how we can continue to advance health technology to improve patient care, health equity, data exchange, and interoperability.What: #ONCTechForumWhen: September 10 and 17, 2021&#xA;Read on healthit.gov</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Policies, Techies &amp;amp; VCs  What&#39;s Next for Health Care?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/policies--techies--amp--vcs---what-s-next-for-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 15:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/policies--techies--amp--vcs---what-s-next-for-health-care/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Next for Health Care?&#xA;Read on whatsnexthealthcare.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Data Interoperability with the National Coordinator for Health IT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/advancing-data-interoperability-with-the-national-coordinator-for-health-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 02:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/advancing-data-interoperability-with-the-national-coordinator-for-health-it/</guid>
      <description>Join this interactive fishbowl discussion as we explore the next steps towards an interoperable health care system with Micky Tripathi.&#xA;Read on eventbrite.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: From Dx to Rx: Collaborating for a Better Patient Experience in Cancer. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--from-dx-to-rx--collaborating-for-a-better-patient-experience-in-cancer--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 16:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--from-dx-to-rx--collaborating-for-a-better-patient-experience-in-cancer--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>The complexity of cancer types and treatments presents a challenge for patients, physicians and researchers in cancer, and can leave patients with gaps in information that alienate them from the decision process. The mCODE project is standardizing data to inform a better experience for cancer patients, from diagnosis to personalized clinical trials and treatment recommendations. mCODE is creating common, easily shared data to drive joint decision making between patients and their treating physicians.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Views from the Top</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/views-from-the-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/views-from-the-top/</guid>
      <description>Be inspired by compelling stories from high-ranking leaders in a variety of industries in top-level, strategic education sessions with Views from the Top.&#xA;Read on himss.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 Annual Research Meeting </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2021-annual-research-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 16:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2021-annual-research-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Event&#xA;Leading with evidence in a time of change&#xA;Bringing the Health Services Research Community Together Virtually In June 2021, health services researchers, policy analysts, clinicians and community members using evidence and data to transform health and health care will once again convene virtually for the AcademyHealth Annual Research Meeting (ARM). An important annual milestone for the community, the ARM is AcademyHealths biggest and most popular meeting of the year, offering an irreplaceable forum for connection, recognition, reflection, learning and professional networking opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/catalyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 15:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/catalyst/</guid>
      <description>Free Live Web Event&#xA;June 10, 2021&#xA;12:00 pm - 1:45 pm EDT&#xA;Virtual Event&#xA;The Covid-19 pandemic exposed the gaps that can occur when the patient voice isnt heard or integrated into the delivery of care. Patients are demanding change in how they receive and consume health care, and providers are responding. Join NEJM Catalyst for the second event in our free, four-part virtual series on how care delivery will change in the coming decade: Health Care 2030: Patients &amp;amp; Consumers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: HIPAA for Dummies Part II. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--hipaa-for-dummies-part-ii--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--hipaa-for-dummies-part-ii--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Youre not dummies! But the legal protections surrounding health data are complicated, and were here to help. Join us for a reboot of our popular first HIPAA for Dummies webinar, during which well break down the HIPAA law, its regulations, and detail the wild western landscape of protections for health data once it leaves the traditional health care system. Well also give an update on the new CMS and ONC Rules affecting individual access to health data, and update you on proposed changes to HIPAA currently under review at HHS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speakers Sessions </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/speakers-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 13:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/speakers-sessions/</guid>
      <description>At their patient experience events, Cleveland Clinic and HIMSS convene clinical thought leaders and patient advocates to address the integral roles empathy and innovation play in improving the care experience.&#xA;Read on empathyandinnovation.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interoperability Lessons for the Post-Pandemic Era </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/interoperability-lessons-for-the-post-pandemic-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 12:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/interoperability-lessons-for-the-post-pandemic-era/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 public health emergency has shone a spotlight on many gaps in health information exchange and data reporting infrastructure across the U.S. But with the crisis have come some valuable l&#xA;Read on himsslearn.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webinar: Avoiding interoperability penalties</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/webinar--avoiding-interoperability-penalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 03:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/webinar--avoiding-interoperability-penalties/</guid>
      <description>In April, federal rules aimed at improving health information exchange will take hold following a year-long delay due to COVID-19. The rules are expected to force a culture change across the industry, according to the top federal health IT official, Micky Tripathi. Regulators will closely monitor whether the new regulations make information more easily available to patients, including through patients mobile apps. So, what can you do to make sure that your organization is prepared to implement operational and business responses and not be vulnerable to penalties?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: NYSHealth Webinar: Supporting Patient and Family Access to Health Information. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--nyshealth-webinar--supporting-patient-and-family-access-to-health-information--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--nyshealth-webinar--supporting-patient-and-family-access-to-health-information--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>The 21st Century CURES Act, a federal mandate that supports patients&amp;rsquo; access to and control of their medical records, recently went into effect. Health care systems are now required to share clinical notes with patients, free of charge. When patients have access to their own visit notes written by health care providers, they better remember what was discussed during the visit; feel more in control of their care; are more likely to take medications as prescribed; and can share notes with their caregivers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 ONC Annual Meeting </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2021-onc-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 19:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2021-onc-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>MARCH 29 - 30, 2021 | 12:00 PM 5:00 PM ET, Register TodayRegister today for the all-virtual 2021 ONC Annual Meeting, held March 29-30 from noon until 5:00 pm ET. Join over 1,000 health IT partners online for two afternoons of plenary and breakout sessions on a variety of topics at the forefront of health IT.Stay tuned for the full agenda be the first to know all the details by subscribing to our weekly email updates and following us on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenNotes Drop-In Clinic Prepares U.S. Healthcare Professionals for Federal Rule Mandating Open Visit Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/opennotes--drop-in-clinic--prepares-u-s--healthcare-professionals-for-federal-rule-mandating-open-visit-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 03:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/opennotes--drop-in-clinic--prepares-u-s--healthcare-professionals-for-federal-rule-mandating-open-visit-notes/</guid>
      <description>March 12, 2021&#xA;What is the OpenNotes Drop-In Clinic? Monday, March 29, through Friday, April 2, for two hours each day, U.S. healthcare professionals are welcome to drop in, for just a few minutes or for the full two hours, to pose questions to a panel of experts about open visit notes (open notes) and transparent clinician-patient communication.&#xA;The OpenNotes Drop-In Clinic will be staffed by clinicians, researchers, and implementation experts standing by via Zoom to answer questions and connect people with resources in advance of a federal mandate requiring complete medical records transparency beginning Monday, April 5.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar - Understanding ONCs Draft USCDI v2 and SVAP. After registering you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar---understanding-oncs-draft-uscdi-v2-and-svap--after-registering-you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 15:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar---understanding-oncs-draft-uscdi-v2-and-svap--after-registering-you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: Understanding ONCs Draft USCDI v2 and SVAP. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.&#xA;Read on zoom.us</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Oncology Notes:Research &amp;amp; Real-World ExperienceWebinar &amp;amp; Office Hours: March 8 &amp;amp; March 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/open-oncology-notes-research--amp--real-world-experiencewebinar--amp--office-hours--march-8--amp--march-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 13:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/open-oncology-notes-research--amp--real-world-experiencewebinar--amp--office-hours--march-8--amp--march-11/</guid>
      <description>February 19, 2021&#xA;Starting this spring U.S. patients will have access to all of their inpatient and ambulatory visit clinical notes (open notes). As the result of a federal information sharing mandate, once clinical notes are signed by a clinician, patients will be able to read them via their online patient portals. In the practice of oncology, this kind of transparency and immediate access to information may represent a culture change for health care providers, patients, and their care partners.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eFax Corporate Webinar </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/efax-corporate-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 19:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/efax-corporate-webinar/</guid>
      <description>February 25, 2021&#xA;Thursday&#xA;9:00 AM to 10:00 AM&#xA;Pacific Time&#xA;On December 10, 2020, HHS announced proposed revisions to the HIPAA Privacy Rule that would significantly impact covered entities under HIPAA. The Proposed Rule is part of HHSs Regulatory Sprint to Coordinated Care, which seeks to promote value-based care by examining federal regulations that impede efforts among health care providers and health plans to better coordinate care for patients. On this Answers Media Network and eFax Corporate webinar, two privacy and security experts will examine key provisions outlined in the rule.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portraits of Resilience:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/portraits-of-resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 12:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/portraits-of-resilience/</guid>
      <description>Inspire and Health Story Collaborative will host a live virtual story session on Feb. 11 to examine resilience in the face of illness.&#xA;Read on corp.inspire.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: ONC Information Blocking FAQ Webinar. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--onc-information-blocking-faq-webinar--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 20:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--onc-information-blocking-faq-webinar--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Join ONC for an informational webinar on the issued Information Blocking (IB) Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs). Speakers will identify important dates and events, provide insight into the January 2021 IB FAQs, discuss ONCs future approach to IB guidance and education, and answer questions from the audience.&#xA;Read on zoom.us</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Digital Transformation in 2021: What&#39;s Next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-digital-transformation-in-2021--what-s-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 13:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-digital-transformation-in-2021--what-s-next/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare Digital Transformation in 2021: What&amp;rsquo;sNext?&#xA;Read on go.carium.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13th Annual Conference on the Science of Dissemination and Implementation in Health </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/13th-annual-conference-on-the-science-of-dissemination-and-implementation-in-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 23:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/13th-annual-conference-on-the-science-of-dissemination-and-implementation-in-health/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Event&#xA;Bridging the gap between research, practice, and policy.&#xA;The Annual Conference on the Science of Dissemination and Implementation in Health (D&amp;amp;I), co-hosted by the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and AcademyHealth, helps realize the full potential of evidence to optimize health and health care by bridging the gap between research, practice, and policy.&#xA;Stay Connected Sign up to receive up-to-date information about the 13th Annual Conference on the Science of Dissemination and Implementation in Health</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Cybersecurity Experience with Gabrielle Hempel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-cybersecurity-experience-with-gabrielle-hempel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-cybersecurity-experience-with-gabrielle-hempel/</guid>
      <description>As healthcare organizations look back at their response to the COVID-19 pandemic, theres a lot that can be learned and applied to a healthcare organizations cybersecurity incident res&#xA;Read on expo.health</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NODE.Health Digital Medicine Conference </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/node-health-digital-medicine-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 16:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/node-health-digital-medicine-conference/</guid>
      <description>Join us for this weeklong virtual event that is unlike any other. Youll leave feeling inspired, energized, and thinking differently about the future of healthcare.At NODE.Health, we believe that evidence is the key to transforming innovative digital health concepts into viable, real-world digital medicine. Thats why, each year, we assemble thought leaders from across the continuumnot just to talk about digital health, but to collaborate on strategies and best practices for implementing evidence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: Accelerating APIs in Healthcare: A Year in Review and Momentum for 2021. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--accelerating-apis-in-healthcare--a-year-in-review-and-momentum-for-2021--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--accelerating-apis-in-healthcare--a-year-in-review-and-momentum-for-2021--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Accelerating APIs in Healthcare: A Year in Review and Momentum for 2021DescriptionJoin us on December 1, 2020, as we spotlight how application programming interface (API)-forward policies and industry actions are accelerating interoperability. This event will include updates from federal agencies as well as presentations and demos from industry partners that highlight how work underway is advancing innovation and competition in the health IT ecosystem. A panel discussion will also be held at the end of the day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health IT Resiliency Experience with Rasu Shrestha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/health-it-resiliency-experience-with-rasu-shrestha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/health-it-resiliency-experience-with-rasu-shrestha/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare organizations have faced so many challenges amidst the COVID-19 pandemic. As we all battle through these challenges, we have the opportunity to adjust our sails and use CO&#xA;Read on expo.health</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIN  Events</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/ain---events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 18:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/ain---events/</guid>
      <description>Platinum Sponsor Speakers Scott Stuewe President &amp;amp; CEO, DirectTrust&#xA;David Schoolcraft Partner, Ogden Murphy Wallace PLLC&#xA;Nancy Beavin Director, Program Delivery, Humana Inc.&#xA;Ryan Howells Principal, Leavitt Partners &amp;amp; Carin Alliance&#xA;Mark J. Segal, PhD, FHIMSS Principal, Digital Health Policy Advisors, LLC&#xA;Kirk Nahra Partner &amp;amp; Co-Chair, Cybersecurity and Privacy Practice, WilmerHale&#xA;Lucia Savage, JD Chief Privacy &amp;amp; Regulatory Officer, Omada Health&#xA;Lygeia Ricciardi President, Clear Voice Consulting&#xA;Steven R.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview  AIN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/overview---ain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 02:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/overview---ain/</guid>
      <description>While there have been many events on interoperability and data sharing, whats unique here is our focus on the BUSINESS rationale for health data sharing.The bases of competition in healthcare are shifting to competing on quality, cost, and patient experience. This shift creates a business imperative to share information, not to hoard it.Hoarding data is not only bad for business but can be catastrophic in a crisis.Data of all kinds has an important role in public health, logistics management, and the healthcare supply chain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transformation Experience with Ed Marx</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/digital-transformation-experience-with-ed-marx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/digital-transformation-experience-with-ed-marx/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest barriers to digital transformation in healthcare is the lack of a codified plan. We are pleased to have Ed Marx, Chief Digital Officer at Tech Mahindra Health and Life Sci&#xA;Read on expo.health</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 PCORI Virtual Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2020-pcori-virtual-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 17:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2020-pcori-virtual-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>The 2020 PCORI Annual Meeting, Accelerating Impact on Care and Patient-Centered Outcomes, will be held virtually this year. Join colleagues from across the healthcare community virtually for PCORIs flagship event to learn more about PCORI-funded studies that can help patients and those who care for them make better-informed healthcare choices.&#xA;Read on pcorievents.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC FHIR at Scale Taskforce (FAST) Workshop: An Architectural Framework for Ecosystem Infrastructure </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-fhir-at-scale-taskforce--fast--workshop--an-architectural-framework-for-ecosystem-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 02:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-fhir-at-scale-taskforce--fast--workshop--an-architectural-framework-for-ecosystem-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Monday, September 14, 2020; 08:30 AM EDT 5:00 PM ET, Join ONC and members of the FHIR at Scale Taskforce (FAST) initiative for a full day workshop titled: FAST, An Architectural Framework for Ecosystem Infrastructure. Having developed andproposed solutionsto addresstechnical infrastructure challengesassociated with deploying FHIR solutions at scale, theFASTcommunity now seeks to explore and solicit feedback on the both the architectural considerations and pathways to implementation for each of these solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC Working Session #2: Patient Identity and Matching </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-working-session--2--patient-identity-and-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 02:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-working-session--2--patient-identity-and-matching/</guid>
      <description>Monday, August 31, 2020; 09:30 AM EDT - 04:30 PM EDT, Join us for a final working session on patient identity and patient matching. We invite individuals and organizations to provide input and insight into existing challenges and promising innovations in patient identity and matching. This final session will focus on the following key areas: privacy and security, research and evaluation, standards, and innovation. This feedback will inform ONCs report to Congress on evaluating the effectiveness of technical and operational methods that improve identification of patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summit Schedule  CCCC Annual Palliative Care Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/summit-schedule---cccc-annual-palliative-care-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 03:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/summit-schedule---cccc-annual-palliative-care-summit/</guid>
      <description>AT-A-GLANCE (complete details coming soon) **DAY 1: Monday, August 24 **&#xA;8:00 am 12 noon | **Summit Sessions&#xA;**&#xA;**DAY 2: Tuesday, August 25 **&#xA;8:00 am 12 noon | Summit Sessions&#xA;Read on ccccsummit.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#WTFix Virtual Patient Panel: Sharing Personal Experiences to Help Improve Health Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/wtfix-virtual-patient-panel--sharing-personal-experiences-to-help-improve-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/wtfix-virtual-patient-panel--sharing-personal-experiences-to-help-improve-health-care/</guid>
      <description>#WTFix Virtual Patient Panel: Sharing Personal Experiences to Help Improve Health Care&#xA;Read on pages.healthsparq.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engaging Patients in Digital Communications During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/engaging-patients-in-digital-communications-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 04:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/engaging-patients-in-digital-communications-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>The panel will discuss innovative solutions that enable digital communications to connect within the healthcare ecosystem. Our panelists will also explore how these kinds of tools empower patients and caregivers to engage in dialogue and facilitate connections betweenstakeholders to inform the health of individuals and communities.&#xA;Read on himss.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Agenda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/full-agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 03:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/full-agenda/</guid>
      <description>Conference Schedule How to Maintain Patient Loyalty as Consumer Culture Drives Healthcare&#xA;Read on gotelehealth.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome! You are invited to join a webinar: Changing the paradigm of patient centricity: are you #researchready. After registering, you will receive a confirmation email about joining the webinar.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--changing-the-paradigm-of-patient-centricity--are-you--researchready--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/welcome--you-are-invited-to-join-a-webinar--changing-the-paradigm-of-patient-centricity--are-you--researchready--after-registering--you-will-receive-a-confirmation-email-about-joining-the-webinar/</guid>
      <description>In the rush to launch solutions to maintain trials during COVID-19 are sponsors at risk for leaving patient input behind?While patient-centricity is an overused term with no real definition, does the current environment allow us the opportunity to rethink how patients are engaged for clinical trials, from trial design to access and participation?Can we create a new more permanent solution where the patient is at the heart of the trial?Join us as a panel of experts who will discuss how this could be done and what the industry should consider, with an actionable plan for implementation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DirectTrust Summit 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/directtrust-summit-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/directtrust-summit-2020/</guid>
      <description>Were going virtual! DirectTrust is proud to host our second annual DirectTrust Summit to connect you with some of the nations greatest healthcare and interoperability experts. Both members and non-members are encouraged to attend, but advance registration is required.&#xA;Read on dt-dts20.myconferencenow.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC Working Session: Patient Identity and Matching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-working-session--patient-identity-and-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/onc-working-session--patient-identity-and-matching/</guid>
      <description>ONC Working Session: Patient Identity and Matching&#xA;Monday, June 1, 2020, 9:30 AM - 4:30 PM ET&#xA;Join us for a working session on patient identity and patient matching. We invite individuals and organizations to provide input and insight into existing challenges and promising innovations in patient identity and matching. This feedback will inform ONCs report to Congress on evaluating the effectiveness of technical and operational methods that improve identification of patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASCO 2020    </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/asco-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 19:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/asco-2020/</guid>
      <description>The American Society of Clinical Oncology (ASCO) 2020 annual meeting will take place from 29th May to 2nd June, 2020 in Chicago, IL. ASCO offers premier scientific events for oncology professionals, patient advocates, industry representatives, and major media outlets worldwide.&#xA;Read on asco-2020.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Health Systems Digital Transformation: Why Digital Health Must Be the New Standard in a Post-COVID-19 World </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/accelerating-health-systems--digital-transformation--why-digital-health-must-be-the-new-standard-in-a-post-covid-19-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 16:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/accelerating-health-systems--digital-transformation--why-digital-health-must-be-the-new-standard-in-a-post-covid-19-world/</guid>
      <description>How can health professionals evolve their practices? What do health systems need to consider when investing in interoperable solutions? What are the implications of critical settings on patients privacy? How can data governance in a post-COVID-19 world set the foundation for future health emergencies? Highlighting the guidance from the WHO Global Strategy on Digital Health, leading global health and technology experts discuss the framework adjustments that will be needed to harness our digital capabilities and create data ecosystems that efficiently tackle future crises.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual FHIR Connectathon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/virtual-fhir-connectathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 11:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/virtual-fhir-connectathon/</guid>
      <description>The Virtual FHIR Connectathon will be three days of hands-on FHIR development and testing. This event provides a great opportunity for implementers and developers to gain hands-on experience developing FHIR-based solutions by participating in one of many tracks. To learn more about the FHIR Connectathon, visit the HL7 FHIR Connectathon 24 page.&#xA;Read on hl7.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eFax Corporate Webinar CMS and ONC Final Rules Implementing Provisions of the 21st Century Cures Act and Impact on your Organization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/efax-corporate-webinar-cms-and-onc-final-rules-implementing-provisions-of-the-21st-century-cures-act-and-impact-on-your-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 20:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/efax-corporate-webinar-cms-and-onc-final-rules-implementing-provisions-of-the-21st-century-cures-act-and-impact-on-your-organization/</guid>
      <description>On March 6, 2020, HHS released two landmark rules one from CMS and one from ONC that implement interoperability and patient access provisions of the 21st Century Cures Act. The rules will impact providers, patients, payors and vendors.&#xA;The CMS Interoperability and Patient Access final rule is focused on driving interoperability and patient access to health information by liberating patient data using CMS authority to regulate Medicare Advantage, Medicaid, CHIP, and Qualified Health Plan issuers on the Federally-facilitated Exchanges (FFEs).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Access of PHI and Communications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/patient-access-of-phi-and-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 10:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/patient-access-of-phi-and-communications/</guid>
      <description>**Patient Access of PHI and Communications - Managing Requests, Texting, and E-mail****Key Points:*** HIPAA and CLIA regulations* New Guidance from the HHS Office of Civil Rights onthe access of PHI* Denials of access* How e-mail and texting should be handled* HIPAA audit and enforcement activities [Read on symposiumgo.com](https://www.symposiumgo.com/webinar/patient-access-of-phi-and-communications---managing-requests-texting-and-e-mail)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>title</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/title/</guid>
      <description>The THCB Gang: Episode 5Apr 15, 2020 0Episode 5 of The THCB Gang is going to be live-streamed Thursday, April 16 at 1pm PT- 4pm ET! 4-6 semi-regular guests drawn from THCB authors and other assorted old friends of mine will shoot the sh*t about health care business, politics, practice, and tech. It tries to be fun but serious and informative! If you miss it, it will also be preserved as a weekly podcast available on ouriTunes&amp;amp;Spotifychannels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Collaborative Health Conversation on Policy &amp; Regulatory Changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/a-collaborative-health-conversation-on-policy---regulatory-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 13:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/a-collaborative-health-conversation-on-policy---regulatory-changes/</guid>
      <description>Washington and many states and local governments have responded to COVID-19 by changing regulations at an unprecedented pace. Join Grace Cordovano, PhD, BCPA and Matt Fisher as they discuss the implications for healthcare providers and businesses, and also for patients and caregivers.&#xA;Read on bigmarker.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare IoT Data at the Point of Care-Registration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-iot-data-at-the-point-of-care-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 04:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/healthcare-iot-data-at-the-point-of-care-registration/</guid>
      <description>IoT is here to stay. Smaller devices and more intelligent sensors, combined with the advent of 5G, are ushering in a new era of patient-generated data. Intelligence at the edge also opens the door to distributed Artificial Intelligence (AI) and analytics. Join us for this amazing discussion on Healthcare IoT Data at the Point of Care to learn how to build out your Edge and IoT ecosystem both at the hospital and at the patients home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health Sciences Summit Overview   </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/health-sciences-summit-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 20:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/health-sciences-summit-overview/</guid>
      <description>The healthcare and life sciences landscape has changed drastically in the last few years. This has led to a fundamental shift from the era of Life Sciences into an era of Health Sciences that focuses on what OZ calls the Human Experience.&#xA;Read on offers.followoz.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preconference Events    </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/preconference-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 19:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/preconference-events/</guid>
      <description>EXPERIENCE REIMAGINEDHealthcare leaders at the forefront of the global patient experience movement will address which systems, tools and insights revolutionize the role of the patient and the caregiver. Well explore patient perspectives and clinical considerations to understand how empathy and innovation must be incorporated as integral pillars to deliver the best clinical, physical and emotional experience in healthcare.&#xA;Read on empathyandinnovation.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health Dev Jam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/health-dev-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 04:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/health-dev-jam/</guid>
      <description>Data access, consumer APIs, and patient empowerment are the future of health data interoperability. Patient empowerment and data access are key pillars of the proposed Patient Access and Interoperability rule. With the ONC and CMS rules in the final stage of review, the reality of patients getting timely electronic access to their health information to make more informed decisions about their care is here. Health Dev Jam will bring together a community of healthcare developers, innovation leaders, designers, researchers, policymakers, and tech enthusiasts to enable interoperability across an open-source API ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient-Centricity is Dead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/patient-centricity-is-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 19:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/patient-centricity-is-dead/</guid>
      <description>HIMSS Global Health Conference &amp;amp; Exhibition: Find out what&amp;rsquo;s next in health.&#xA;Read on himssconference.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of the Industry Panel: Patient Engagement and Experience </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/state-of-the-industry-panel--patient-engagement-and-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 12:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/state-of-the-industry-panel--patient-engagement-and-experience/</guid>
      <description>Patient satisfaction and engagement are keys to better care, and as consumerism continues to trans&#xA;Read on himssconference.org</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 Health Datapalooza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2020-health-datapalooza/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 19:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2020-health-datapalooza/</guid>
      <description>Event&#xA;Co-located with the National Health Policy Conference&#xA;For more than 10 years, the Health Datapalooza has been turning information into innovation by supporting a healthy exchange of ideas from a variety of voices in a setting where meaningful and consequential conversations take place.&#xA;Co-Located with the National Health Policy Conference As an additional benefit to this year&amp;rsquo;s show, Health Datapalooza attendees will gain new opportunities (if you choose) to engage in expansive discussions with participants across the hall&amp;quot; at the National Health Policy Conference (NHPC) and pick and choose relevant sessions to attend from both events.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 ONC Annual Meeting </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/2020-onc-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 05:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/2020-onc-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>January 27-28, 2020, Registration has now closed. Space-available registration will be available again onsite.Registerfor the 2020 ONC Annual Meeting! This years event, Connecting Policy and Technology: Bringing the EHR to the Patient, will be held January 27-28 at the JW Marriott in Washington, DC. The eventwill gather approximately 1,200 health IT partners for a combination of plenaries and breakout sessions covering a variety of health IT, healthcare, and innovation topics. Make your hotel reservation no later than December 3, 2019 to access the special group rate at the JW Marriott.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
