<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare IT News on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthcare-it-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare IT News on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:05:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthcare-it-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to fix EHRs? One health IT leader has some ideas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/how-to-fix-ehrs--one-health-it-leader-has-some-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/how-to-fix-ehrs--one-health-it-leader-has-some-ideas/</guid>
      <description>EHR technologies that unify seamlessly with practice management and patient engagement tools allow clinicians to deliver high-quality care consistently. When technologies are leveraged to encourage and maintain patient involvement in their own care, it&amp;rsquo;s evident in their outcomes as patients progress toward treatment goals, particularly when related to lifestyle changes and medication management.Health IT leaders must continue to invest in technologies that guide effective chronic disease management. While today&amp;rsquo;s chronic care patients are better off than those in decades past, engaged patients of the future will reap further benefits of smarter, well-integrated technologies</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HHS Secretary: Cures Act enforcement &#39;long overdue&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/hhs-secretary--cures-act-enforcement--long-overdue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 01:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/hhs-secretary--cures-act-enforcement--long-overdue/</guid>
      <description>Among them arewhat he referred to as the Cures Act penalty enforcement gap. Namely, as Becerra explained, civil monetary penalties for not complying with information-sharing requirements have only been established for technology developers and health information networks. &amp;ldquo;It left the provider penalty up to me: the secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services,&amp;rdquo; he said. This is an issue, he noted, because more than 75% of the complaints submitted to ONC have been about providers and most have come from patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So TEFCA is live. Now what?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/so-tefca-is-live--now-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 11:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/so-tefca-is-live--now-what/</guid>
      <description>Global Edition2022 Look AheadSo TEFCA is live. Now what?Former National Coordinator for Health IT Dr. Don Rucker discusses what&amp;rsquo;s next for interoperability and why he sees TEFCA as a &amp;lsquo;solid first step.&amp;lsquo;By Kat JercichJanuary 24, 202202:58 PMPhoto: HIMSS MediaThis past week, the U.S. Office of the National Coordinator for Health IT announced that the Trusted Exchange Framework and Common Agreement is now live. The announcement marks a major step forward toward nationwide interoperability, aimed at simplifying inter-organizational connectivity and ultimately giving individuals access to their healthcare information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interoperability: Where it&#39;s headed, and where IT leaders will be investing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/interoperability--where-it-s-headed--and-where-it-leaders-will-be-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 16:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/interoperability--where-it-s-headed--and-where-it-leaders-will-be-investing/</guid>
      <description>Five CIOs, a COO and a CMIO chart a course for the complex demands of data exchange, and discuss the technologies and strategies they plan to focus on in the next five years.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIO must-dos: Reduce bureaucracy, boost patient experience and improve data governance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/cio-must-dos--reduce-bureaucracy--boost-patient-experience-and-improve-data-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 16:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/cio-must-dos--reduce-bureaucracy--boost-patient-experience-and-improve-data-governance/</guid>
      <description>Now providers must also deliver it in a more patient-friendly platform.If they do not, another provider in-person or virtual is ready to step in and fill the void, he added.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confusion remains about ONC information blocking rules, even after start date</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/confusion-remains-about-onc-information-blocking-rules--even-after-start-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 20:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/confusion-remains-about-onc-information-blocking-rules--even-after-start-date/</guid>
      <description>Tripathi and Posnack explained that for the next 18 months, the information that can&amp;rsquo;t be &amp;ldquo;blocked&amp;rdquo; is limited to the data elements represented in the United States Core Data for Interoperability.&amp;ldquo;This initial 18-month period and limited scope gives the regulated community time to grow more experienced with the information blocking regulation, including when and how to meet an &amp;rsquo;exception,&amp;rsquo; before the full scope of the regulations EHI definition comes into effect,&amp;rdquo; they wrote.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIMSSCast: What the new info blocking rules mean for you  with Deven McGraw</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/himsscast--what-the-new-info-blocking-rules-mean-for-you---with-deven-mcgraw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 03:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/himsscast--what-the-new-info-blocking-rules-mean-for-you---with-deven-mcgraw/</guid>
      <description>Ciitizen&amp;rsquo;s Deven McGraw, formerly of OCR and ONC, breaks down the big health policy changes coming our way.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC chief Micky Tripathi talks public health data systems and &#39;health equity by design&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/onc-chief-micky-tripathi-talks-public-health-data-systems-and--health-equity-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 02:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/onc-chief-micky-tripathi-talks-public-health-data-systems-and--health-equity-by-design/</guid>
      <description>As he focuses on shoring up data-sharing resiliency and ensuring that new IT initiatives bake in SDOH as a &amp;ldquo;fundamental design criterion,&amp;rdquo; the new national coordinator also reminded people about an important April 5 start date.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micky Tripathi named by Biden administration to lead ONC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/micky-tripathi-named-by-biden-administration-to-lead-onc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 14:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/micky-tripathi-named-by-biden-administration-to-lead-onc/</guid>
      <description>As National Coordinator for Health IT, the interoperability veteran will bring deep standards expertise as the rubber hits the road on nationwide API-based data exchange.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is HIPAA outdated? AHIMA questions whether law is keeping pace with change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/is-hipaa-outdated--ahima-questions-whether-law-is-keeping-pace-with-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 18:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/is-hipaa-outdated--ahima-questions-whether-law-is-keeping-pace-with-change/</guid>
      <description>The law was enacted when the internet was in its infancy and healthcare was still paper-based.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With telehealth, one size won&#39;t fit all</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/with-telehealth--one-size-won-t-fit-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 13:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/with-telehealth--one-size-won-t-fit-all/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not just caregivers and clinicians who have had to master the new modality for delivering care; healthcare consumers and their extended network of family and friends now have to adapt to telehealth as a new normal in accessing and receiving care.The most mature health systems recognize the importance of context and design their telehealth programs accordingly. Telehealth looks different for millennials and retirees, rural and urban inner-city populations, and population groups with fundamentally different healthcare needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayo Clinic sued over breach of patient health records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/mayo-clinic-sued-over-breach-of-patient-health-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 20:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/mayo-clinic-sued-over-breach-of-patient-health-records/</guid>
      <description>Patients filed class-action complaints against the Mayo Clinic this past week. They areaccusing the system of violating the Minnesota Health Records Act. Mayo Clinic said in a news release in October that a former employee had inappropriately accessed the health records of more than 1,600 patients. Now, multiple patients are seeking to have a class-action case declared against the clinic.According to a complaint filed last week in Olmsted County District Court, Mayo Clinic told plaintiff Olga Ryabchuk that the potentially accessible data included her name, demographic information, birth date, medical record number and clinical notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC offers new compliance extension for information blocking rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/onc-offers-new-compliance-extension-for-information-blocking-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/onc-offers-new-compliance-extension-for-information-blocking-rules/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare stakeholders will have a bit of extra time to get their ducks in a row for the information blocking rules and IT certification requirements outlined in the 21st Century Cures Act.The original due date was coming soon: next Monday, November 2.The info blocking applicability date is now April 5, 2021 while new requirements around standardized API functionality havebeen pushed out to New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve 2022.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ONC officials offer update on information blocking rules compliance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/onc-officials-offer-update-on-information-blocking-rules-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 02:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/onc-officials-offer-update-on-information-blocking-rules-compliance/</guid>
      <description>Wherever the new date might be moved, it will eventually arrive. In the meantime, those covered by the rules healthcare providers, developers of certified health IT, health information networks and health information exchanges should continue to prepare, he said.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New interoperability rulings push the needle on FHIR adoption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/new-interoperability-rulings-push-the-needle-on-fhir-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 23:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/new-interoperability-rulings-push-the-needle-on-fhir-adoption/</guid>
      <description>Diameter Health President John D&amp;rsquo;Amore discusses the ONC and CMS rulings and the future of interoperability in the U.S.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unencrypted stolen laptop costs Lifespan more than $1M</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/unencrypted-stolen-laptop-costs-lifespan-more-than--1m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/unencrypted-stolen-laptop-costs-lifespan-more-than--1m/</guid>
      <description>OCR Director Roger Severino agrees. In a statement on the Lifespan case, he put it simply:&amp;ldquo;Laptops, cellphones, and other mobile devices are stolen every day, thats the hard reality,&amp;rdquo; said Severino. &amp;ldquo;Covered entities can best protect their patients&amp;rsquo; data by encrypting mobile devices to thwart identity thieves.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three ways providers get HIPAA right of access wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/three-ways-providers-get-hipaa-right-of-access-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 13:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/three-ways-providers-get-hipaa-right-of-access-wrong/</guid>
      <description>On another front, some entities also struggle with digital signature, she said.How do I know the patient has actually signed this request form when it is done digitally? McGraw asked. That I think is an open question that can be difficult to solve. But nevertheless, you have to have a way for people to be able to remotely request their information, because you cant require an in-person visit. The guidance makes this very clear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress must tackle patient matching amid COVID-19, says Pew Charitable Trusts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/congress-must-tackle-patient-matching-amid-covid-19--says-pew-charitable-trusts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 18:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/congress-must-tackle-patient-matching-amid-covid-19--says-pew-charitable-trusts/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;As Congress looks to enhance the nations capacity to respond to this pandemic, improving patient matching will be critical,&amp;rdquo; said Ben Moscovitch, project director for health information technology at the Pew Charitable Trusts.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open health data privacy debate set to drive post-COVID-19 planning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/open-health-data-privacy-debate-set-to-drive-post-covid-19-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/open-health-data-privacy-debate-set-to-drive-post-covid-19-planning/</guid>
      <description>More widely, patient confidence will also be an important aspect of any preparation for post-COVID healthcare, said Dr Dilruwan Chaminda Herath, executive medical director UK and Ireland for MSD, who also contributed to the Public Policy Projects discussion. The new normal for patient pathways will have been transformed. Collaboration between stakeholders and focus on the synergy between different disciplines will be central to services getting up and running again and the emphasis must be on the total patient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 highlights the importance of ONC info blocking rules, says Rucker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/covid-19-highlights-the-importance-of-onc-info-blocking-rules--says-rucker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 20:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/covid-19-highlights-the-importance-of-onc-info-blocking-rules--says-rucker/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The main driver here is our consumer expectation that what we&amp;rsquo;re getting in healthcare isn&amp;rsquo;t matching up to what we&amp;rsquo;re getting in other aspects of our lives,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;The patients have a right to that data, for the patients to control and move as they desire, rather than under the control of the providers and payers.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New HHS rule calls for FHIR use cases to aid data exchange</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/new-hhs-rule-calls-for-fhir-use-cases-to-aid-data-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 14:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/new-hhs-rule-calls-for-fhir-use-cases-to-aid-data-exchange/</guid>
      <description>Specifically, the final rules call for payers to provide healthcare data to patients through the use of FHIR-based APIs, as well as using a similar methodology to make provider directories available to patients. The CMS rule mentions two implementation guides developed by the Da Vinci Project &amp;ldquo;that support the policies that we have finalized in this rule,&amp;rdquo; she said.&amp;ldquo;While these implementation guides are not requirements of the rule, we believe they will significantly support and improve the implementation of these APIs on the part of payers,&amp;rdquo; Mugge added.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over half of health care providers noncompliant with HIPAA access rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/over-half-of-health-care-providers-noncompliant-with-hipaa-access-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 22:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/over-half-of-health-care-providers-noncompliant-with-hipaa-access-rules/</guid>
      <description>Some patients who request their medical records still do not receive them within the legally mandated 30-day period or in the format requested, says Deven McGraw, chief regulatory officer at Ciitizen and a former HHS Office for Civil Rights official. An updated scorecard from Ciitizen found compliance with HIPAA Right of Access rules has risen, but 51% of health care providers are noncompliant.&#xA;Read on healthcareitnews.com</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
