<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HealthITSecurity on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthitsecurity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HealthITSecurity on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 19:41:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthitsecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OCR Settles Three HIPAA Right of Access Cases With Dental Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-settles-three-hipaa-right-of-access-cases-with-dental-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 19:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-settles-three-hipaa-right-of-access-cases-with-dental-practices/</guid>
      <description>The HHS Office for Civil Rights (OCR) resolved three HIPAA right of access cases with three dental practices. The resolutions bring OCRs total number of cases to 41 since it launched the HIPAA Right of Access Initiative in 2019.All three cases underscore the importance and necessity of compliance with the HIPAA Rules, OCR stated in its announcement. In July, OCR announced that it had resolved 11 right of access cases, demonstrating its commitment to making sure that patients have access to their medical records.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senators Aim to Ban Data Brokers From Selling Health Data With New Bill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/senators-aim-to-ban-data-brokers-from-selling-health-data-with-new-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 16:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/senators-aim-to-ban-data-brokers-from-selling-health-data-with-new-bill/</guid>
      <description>Along with banning the sale of location and health data by data brokers, the act would require the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate rules for implementing the law within 180 days. The FTC would make certain exceptions for HIPAA-compliant activities, authorized disclosures, and protected First Amendment speech.&#xA;Read on healthitsecurity.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCR Announces Four HIPAA Enforcement Actions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-announces-four-hipaa-enforcement-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 14:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr-announces-four-hipaa-enforcement-actions/</guid>
      <description>he HHS Office for Civil Rights (OCR) announced four HIPAA enforcement actions to hold healthcare providers accountable for potential HIPAA violations. Two of the actions stemmed from OCRs HIPAA Right of Access Initiative, bringing the total number ofenforcement actions to 27 since the initiative began in 2019.Between the rising pace of breaches of unsecured protected health information and continued cyber security threats impacting the health care industry, it is critical that covered entities take their HIPAA compliance responsibilities seriously, Lisa J.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Identification of PHI According to the HIPAA Privacy Rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/de-identification-of-phi-according-to-the-hipaa-privacy-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 03:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/de-identification-of-phi-according-to-the-hipaa-privacy-rule/</guid>
      <description>The two HHS-approved methods for the de-identification of PHI can aid in clinical research while ensuring HIPAA compliance and patient privacy.&#xA;Read on healthitsecurity.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HHS Announces Former DHS Official Lisa J. Pino as New OCR Director</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/hhs-announces-former-dhs-official-lisa-j--pino-as-new-ocr-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/hhs-announces-former-dhs-official-lisa-j--pino-as-new-ocr-director/</guid>
      <description>September 28, 2021 -HHS has appointed Lisa J. Pino as director of the Office for Civil Rights (OCR). OCR oversees civil rights enforcements, HIPAA regulations, security, privacy, and breach notification rules.Most recently, Pino served as the executive deputy commissioner of the New York State Department of Health, where she led New Yorks COVID-19 operational response along with Medicaid, Medicare, AIDS Institute, and the Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC), among others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Northwestern Memorial HealthCare Latest Victim of Elektas PHI Data Breach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/northwestern-memorial-healthcare-latest-victim-of-elekta-s-phi-data-breach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 17:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/northwestern-memorial-healthcare-latest-victim-of-elekta-s-phi-data-breach/</guid>
      <description>he breach impacted a portion of its North American customers. Immediately upon learning of this incident, Elekta partnered with leading cyber experts and law enforcement to launch an investigation to understand what happened, mitigate any possible harm, and offer our customers a reliable solution that delivers on our commitment to ensure that cancer patients have access to precise and personalized radiotherapy treatments, Elekta stated in the release.For the patients at any of Northwestern Memorial HealthCares nine Chicago-area hospitals impacted, a call center is currently set up to answer questions about the incident.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCR: Healthcare HIPAA Compliance Report Finds PHI Security Failures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr--healthcare-hipaa-compliance-report-finds-phi-security-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ocr--healthcare-hipaa-compliance-report-finds-phi-security-failures/</guid>
      <description>In fact, 89 percent of the audited entities failed to comply with access requirements. Another 67 percent failed to comply with providing the necessary content and to document adequate compliance in their breach notifications.&#xA;Read on healthitsecurity.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banner Health to Pay OCR $200K for HIPAA Right of Access Failures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/banner-health-to-pay-ocr--200k-for-hipaa-right-of-access-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 04:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/banner-health-to-pay-ocr--200k-for-hipaa-right-of-access-failures/</guid>
      <description>However, the corrective action plan noted that in signing the settlement with OCR, Banner Health is not admitting liability.&#xA;Read on healthitsecurity.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Premera Pays OCR $6.85M to Settle HIPAA Violations, Breach of 10.4M</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/premera-pays-ocr--6-85m-to-settle-hipaa-violations--breach-of-10-4m/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 14:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/premera-pays-ocr--6-85m-to-settle-hipaa-violations--breach-of-10-4m/</guid>
      <description>he Department of Health and Human Services Office for Civil Rightssettledwith Premera Blue Cross for $6.85 million and a corrective action plan, after an audit into the insurers 2015 data breach that impacted 10.4 million patients revealed systemic noncompliance with the HIPAA rule.The OCR settlement with Premera is the second largest in agency history. The largest was imposed on Anthemfor$16 million, followingits 2015 data breach that affected74 million patients.&#xA;Read on healthitsecurity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
