<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare IT Today | Fresh, Daily, Practical Healthcare IT Insights on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthcare-it-today--fresh-daily-practical-healthcare-it-insights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare IT Today | Fresh, Daily, Practical Healthcare IT Insights on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 12:14:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthcare-it-today--fresh-daily-practical-healthcare-it-insights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Tribute to Casey Quinlan  Advocate and Renaissance Woman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/a-tribute-to-casey-quinlan---advocate-and-renaissance-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 12:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/a-tribute-to-casey-quinlan---advocate-and-renaissance-woman/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday April 25th 2023, the world lost a bright flame. After a long journey with cancer, Casey Quinlan @MightyCasey passed away peacefully with family and friends by her side. Quinlan was one-of-a-kind and if you had the good fortune of meeting her in-person or interacted with her online, she undoubtedly left an impression. She was one of the few people who had zero qualms about speaking her mind and that is one of reasons why I admired her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EHI is Not What it Used to be, but Dont Panic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ehi-is-not-what-it-used-to-be--but-don-t-panic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 14:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ehi-is-not-what-it-used-to-be--but-don-t-panic/</guid>
      <description>What a difference a day makes. On October 6, 2022, the healthcare and health IT community woke to a new reality one in which electronic health information (EHI) included far more than it did the day before. Why was that so important? Because penalties for information blocking that is, any practice that interferes with access, exchange, or use of electronic health data are tied to the definition of EHI. With many more types of health information specifically included as EHI, organizations regulated under the 21st Century Cures Act are on the hook to respond to requests for that information from individuals, providers, public health agencies, and health information exchanges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Can Be Done to Address the Burden on Non-Clinical Staff?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-can-be-done-to-address-the-burden-on-non-clinical-staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 14:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-can-be-done-to-address-the-burden-on-non-clinical-staff/</guid>
      <description>Physician burnout has been and will be a hot topic in every healthcare organization. However, are enough organizations also looking at the burden their non-clinical staff are experiencing? The reality is that if you dont take of your non-clinical staff that has a trickle down effect that impacts patients and doctors. This is a really big problem that needs to be addressed.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Sit Down with Epic to Learn About Their Decision to Support TEFCA </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/a-sit-down-with-epic-to-learn-about-their-decision-to-support-tefca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 13:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/a-sit-down-with-epic-to-learn-about-their-decision-to-support-tefca/</guid>
      <description>No doubt those of you in the world of health IT and interoperability saw the news that Epic plans to apply to join TEFCA as an inaugural QHIN (Qualified Health Information Network). This is big news for TEFCA since its largely a voluntary effort that isnt pushed by some sort of stimulus money or penalties like many past government efforts.We wanted to learn about Epics decision to apply to be a QHIN, so we sat down with Matt Doyle, Software Development Lead for Interoperability at Epic, to talk about this announcement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epics UGM (User) Conference: Insights, Perspectives, and the Experience </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/epic-s-ugm--user--conference--insights--perspectives--and-the-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 11:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/epic-s-ugm--user--conference--insights--perspectives--and-the-experience/</guid>
      <description>Still on my bucket list of conferences to attend is the Epic UGM (User Group Meeting) they hold every year for Epic users. I love user conferences because you hear about the true realities users face. Plus, theres a common bond on the same application that makes finding someone who shares your challenges easy. As []&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights Into EHR Documentation Workstations </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/insights-into-ehr-documentation-workstations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 17:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/insights-into-ehr-documentation-workstations/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important and least covered things in healthcare IT is the various EHR Documentation Workstations. No doubt its a regular topic of conversations at healthcare organizations because an EHR workstation configuration really impacts EHR users experience and therefore the patient. Its not as sexy to talk about workstations when you could talk []&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
