<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Individual Access Services (IAS): Why Patients and Families Should Pay Attention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/individual-access-services-ias--why-patients-and-families-should-pay-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/individual-access-services-ias--why-patients-and-families-should-pay-attention/</guid>
      <description>From since the formal launch of TEFCA at the HHS event in early December 2023, it’s been exhilarating to watch the first IAS queries become a reality. While the majority of the industry has balked at IAS, a partnership between Health Gorilla, Clear, and Unblock Health is lighting the way.&#xA;Many patients and advocates are asking me:&#xA;What does this really mean for patients? So what? Who cares about a new set of acronyms in healthcare, including TEFCA and IAS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Code in AI: the Patient Voice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-missing-code-in-ai_-the-patient-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-missing-code-in-ai_-the-patient-voice/</guid>
      <description>The accompanying image was created by DALL-E. &#39;The Missing Code in AI: The Patient Voice.&#39; Generated image. OpenAI, [1/12/2024]&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s crystal clear that the patient and carepartner voice is not diversely represented in the co-creation of AI-powered solutions used in patient care and patient coordination of care.&#xA;Implementation and integration of AI-powered solutions based on assumptions of what innovators, healthcare executives, and providers think patients and their families need to be successful in their care is a red flag for failure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You Give a Patient a Copy of Her Medical Records(an ode to If You Give a Mouse a Cookie by Laura Numeroff)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/if-you-give-a-patient-a-copy-of-her-medical-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/if-you-give-a-patient-a-copy-of-her-medical-records/</guid>
      <description>If you give a patient a cancer diagnosis, she may request a copy of her medical records. When she gets her medical records, she may pore over them, carefully deciphering their secrets, jotting down notes with a furrowed brow.&#xA;If you present a patient with her medical records, she may begin peppering her doctors with questions about her care. Each question, a step towards understanding, may fuel a desire for a broader perspective and she may seek a second opinion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracking Open the Other Black Box: Unmasking AI&#39;s Role in Patient Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/cracking-open-the-other-black-box-unmasking-ais-role-in-patient-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/cracking-open-the-other-black-box-unmasking-ais-role-in-patient-care/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk breast cancer screening, access to results in the portal, and AI powered breast cancer detection.&#xA;It was exciting to see my local imaging center offering Enhanced Breast Cancer Detection (EBCD) using Deep Health&amp;rsquo;s SAIGE-Dx, a mammography diagnostic aid software.&#xA;As someone who has a family history of breast cancer and extremely dense breasts, I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting routine mammograms with ultrasounds since my early 30&amp;rsquo;s. About 10% of women fall into the category of dense breasts, where it is extremely difficult to detect a tumor on a mammogram.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nightmare on Prior Auth Street</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/nightmare-on-prior-auth-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/nightmare-on-prior-auth-street/</guid>
      <description>With Halloween upon us, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a good scary story or movie?!&#xA;The longer I work in healthcare and in patient advocacy, the more I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize that the real horror stories and things that nightmares are made of often come from the fragmentation and administrative burden that is embedded within US healthcare. These are stories that are all too frequent and stories that I wish no one needed to tell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release the Results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/release-the-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/release-the-results/</guid>
      <description>A recent article published in the Wall Street Journal entitled Raw Medical Test Results Right to Your Inbox Spark Confusion and Concern continues to beat a dead horse. The only thing that is sparking confusion and concern is why we are still debating whether patients can handle their health information as if becoming a patient strips one of being a consenting adult with choices.&#xA;Here are my top four thoughts on this WSJ piece:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Message or not to Message: that is the Question</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/to-message-or-not-to-message-that-is-the-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/to-message-or-not-to-message-that-is-the-question/</guid>
      <description>It’s been months of debate and controversy surrounding what to do about the ever increasing rates of patient portal messages. Healthcare is adept at finding ways to charge for things. And so, along come patient portal messages and this line from this recent article from STAT:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Introducing fees might remind patients that there’s a human on the other end of the patient portal who has to spend time answering each question, pushing them to “pause and think before they send a message.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patients Can’t Wait: It’s Time to Unblock Health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/patients-cant-wait-its-time-to-unblock-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/patients-cant-wait-its-time-to-unblock-health/</guid>
      <description>Ensuring patients have access to the information, tools, and technology they need to make informed decisions about their care is one of the apex of my priorities as a practicing board-certified patient advocate.&#xA;Much of the work patient advocates do is aimed at reducing human suffering. Human suffering presents in many forms. Patient Administrative Burden (PAB) is a significant source of patient suffering. PAB causes extensive barriers to care, especially in the context of a life-altering, life-limiting condition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTI-1 Proposed Rule Public Comments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hti-1-proposed-rule-public-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hti-1-proposed-rule-public-comments/</guid>
      <description>National Coordinator Micky Tripathi&#xA;Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology&#xA;Mary E. Switzer Building&#xA;330 C. St SW, 7th Floor&#xA;Washington, DC 20024&#xA;Re: RIN 0955–AA03; Health Data, Technology, and Interoperability: Certification Program Updates, Algorithm Transparency, and Information Sharing&#xA;June 20, 2023&#xA;Dear Dr. Tripathi:&#xA;As an individual, board-certified patient advocate, the primary carepartner to two disabled adults, and a patient myself, I appreciate the opportunity to provide comments on the Health Data, Technology, and Interoperability Certification Program Updates, Algorithm Transparency, and Information Sharing Proposed Rule (HTI-1).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Five Key Points Missing from the Majority of Digital Health Transformation Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-five-key-points-missing-from-the-majority-of-digital-health-transformation-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-five-key-points-missing-from-the-majority-of-digital-health-transformation-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Grateful for the opportunity to speak at Modern Healthcare&amp;rsquo;s Digital Health Transformation Summit with Rich Steinle,Julie Wolk, Teresa Andrea MSHA, BSN, RN.&#xA;Here are my 5 key points from the patient and carepartner perspective, from our panel as well as the 2 day event, that are of essence to successful digital health transformation strategies:&#xA;Robust digital health transformation strategies must include diverse representation from ALL stakeholders through co-creation with patients and carepartners as a necessary cornerstone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collections &amp; Recollections of Casey Quinlan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/collections--recollections-of-casey-quinlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/collections--recollections-of-casey-quinlan/</guid>
      <description>On April 25, 2023, Casey Quinlan died peacefully after a long journey with metastatic cancer. The tributes, tweets, and social media posts poured in. I wanted to find a place to capture them. So here’s my attempt at a “Collections &amp;amp; Recollections of Casey”.&#xA;I’ll never forget one of my 1st conversations with Casey at MedMo16 in New York City. When I met Casey in person, I had to ask about the QR code she had tattooed on her chest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfers of Care: the Silent Natural Disaster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/transfers-of-care_-the-silent-natural-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/transfers-of-care_-the-silent-natural-disaster/</guid>
      <description>It was 11:20 pm.&#xA;I was digging out from traveling, catching up on emails in the stillness of the night.&#xA;A text alert came through. It was from a patient with metastatic cancer that had transferred to a hospice facility that evening. I assumed it was a regular check-in to say goodnight or “all good here.”&#xA;No dice.&#xA;“Do you have my updated list of my meds?”&#xA;How could a patient with advanced cancer that’s been hospitalized for two weeks and transferred to an in-patient hospice facility not have their health information follow them?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dress in Blue Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dress-in-blue-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/dress-in-blue-day/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that March is National Colorectal Cancer (CRC) Awareness Month?&#xA;Check out the formal announcement by the White House proclaiming March 2023 as National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month.&#xA;March 3rd was Dress In Blue Day, one of the many ways to show support for CRC awareness and share the importance of screening with your loved ones, colleagues, and friends. There were many posts on Twitter, LinkedIN, and Facebook celebrating #DressInBlueDay.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ready, Set, Action! 20 Things You Can Do With Your Medical Records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ready-set-action-20-things-you-can-do-with-your-medical-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ready-set-action-20-things-you-can-do-with-your-medical-records/</guid>
      <description>Our health information is becoming more and more accessible. Did you know that there&amp;rsquo;s more to your medical records than just being able to look at them? Here are 20 things you can do with your medical records.&#xA;Create your personal health record: Having a copy of your medical records can help you keep track of your health and medical history and make it easier for you to share with your doctor and care team as needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blocking Access Through Hidden Dams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/blocking-access-through-hidden-dams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/blocking-access-through-hidden-dams/</guid>
      <description>We are living in an environment where too many providers are pushing back against patients accessing their medical records and health information.&#xA;In my daily patient advocacy work, I am seeing an increase in doctors discouraging:&#xA;portal use patients against reading new lab, pathology, or imaging results signing up for a patient portal. using apps to gather one&amp;rsquo;s health information. Discouraging the use of patient portals and not offering access to portals and individuals&amp;rsquo; information is harmful to patients, hinders the growth of the doctor-patient relationship, and directly causes inequities in care and access to care</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Need-to-Knows The Information Blocking Rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-the-information-blocking-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-the-information-blocking-rules/</guid>
      <description>Around mid to late September 2022, I started hearing an uptick in questions from patients and their families about notices they were receiving from their health care delivery organizations and physicians’ offices about the &amp;ldquo;ability to access more or all of their health information without delay&amp;rdquo;. The Information Blocking Rules October 6, 2022 milestone was around the corner and hospitals, cancer centers, and physicians were attempting to communicate changes to prepare their patients for the anticipated changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Society that Is AI/ML Powered Clinical Decision Support (CDS)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-secret-society-that-is-aiml-powered-clinical-decision-support-cds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-secret-society-that-is-aiml-powered-clinical-decision-support-cds/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m finding that when specifically asked, doctors do not want to discuss the AI/ML/NLP enabled tools they use that may help guide their decision-making about an individual patient&amp;rsquo;s care &amp;amp; care coordination.&#xA;The use of AI/ML/NLP powered clinical decision support (CDS) tools is typically not noted in a patient&amp;rsquo;s medical record.&#xA;Patients do not get a copy of any AI/ML/NLP generated outputs, such as scores, reports, graphs, trends, or alerts that may play a significant role in determining their care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Need-to-Knows: ABCs of HIEs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-abcs-of-hies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-abcs-of-hies/</guid>
      <description>If only there was a central repository of information that patients could access in their time of need….no, I’m not talking about the patient portal.&#xA;While a comprehensive, longitudinal medical record is still only a thing of day dreams, health information exchanges (HIEs) may be a close second. Here’s a bit more on HIEs from HealthIT.gov.&#xA;This episode of Patient Need-to-Knows is all about these seemingly underground pipelines of patient data that exist across the nation that patients have NOT had access to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Efforts to Bridge the Digital Divide Fail, Don’t Blame Patients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-efforts-to-bridge-the-digital-divide-fail-dont-blame-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-efforts-to-bridge-the-digital-divide-fail-dont-blame-patients/</guid>
      <description>The VA recently offered a program which issued devices to veterans to be able to take part in virtual visits; see the excellent overview from John Lynn. The full OIG report is here: https://www.va.gov/oig/pubs/VAOIG-21-02668-182.pdf&#xA;The goal of the program was to bridge the digital divide that existed for many veterans who didn’t have the right device or connectivity to receive virtual care. While the distribution of devices was somewhat successful, program goals had much room for improvement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Can Reduce &amp; Eliminate Patient Medication Errors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/we-can-reduce-eliminate-patient-medication-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/we-can-reduce-eliminate-patient-medication-errors/</guid>
      <description>Errors in patient medication data are a disaster and safety error waiting to happen, especially in cases where there are multiple comorbidities, chronic illness, life-altering, life-limiting conditions and in our elderly populations who frequently have dozens of medications to manage. As the primary carepartner to 2 disabled adults and the carepartner to a loved one with metastatic cancer, I can personally assure you that errors in medications can mean life or death and most definitely be the reason a loved one avoids the ER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Need-to-Knows Data Exchange and Medical Records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-data-exchange-and-medical-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-data-exchange-and-medical-records/</guid>
      <description>Patients, their families, advocates, and consumers face vast gaps of information that they, unfortunately, are NOT connected to in the healthcare arena.&#xA;One of the most common frustrations I hear from patients and their families is:&#xA;&#34;Why don&#39;t my medical records go where they need to go?&#34; Given the nature of our digital world, it’s a logical and acceptable question and frustration. To get to the crux of the matter, I turned to the best subject matter experts on all things health information exchange, interoperability, and medical records in my network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Need-To-Knows: Non-Clinical Uses of Medical Records &amp; Pediatrics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-non-clinical-uses-of-medical-records--pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows-non-clinical-uses-of-medical-records--pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>The healthcare ecosystem largely focuses on clinical uses of health information and medical records data. Did you know that there&amp;rsquo;s a spectrum of non-clinical uses for medical records that ALL individuals should know about?&#xA;In the latest episode of Patient Need-to-Knows, healthcare futurist &amp;amp; rockstar advocate &amp;amp; caregiver, Erica Johansen and I talk about little known ways that individuals can use their medical records to achieve necessary, positive outcomes that are not necessarily clinical in scope.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medical Records &amp; Precision Medicine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/medical-records-precision-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/medical-records-precision-medicine/</guid>
      <description>June is the 10th Annual Cancer Immunotherapy Month hosted by colleagues at Cancer Research Institute (CRI). Working with a global network of researchers, supporters, patients, and advocates, CRI is funding the best scientists doing the most promising research.&#xA;You can learn more about the lifesaving potential of immunotherapy here: https://www.cancerresearch.org/en-us/join-the-cause/cancer-immunotherapy-month&#xA;IMPORTANT FACT : Did you know that immunotherapy is the fourth pillar of cancer treatment?&#xA;Talk to your doctor and care team about the potential of immunotherapy as part of your treatment planning discussions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Need-To-Knows: Working with Oncology Registered Dieticians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows--working-with-oncology-registered-dieticians/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/patient-need-to-knows--working-with-oncology-registered-dieticians/</guid>
      <description>Patients need their medical records for a broad spectrum of things. Being a patient can take significant work to get the care one needs. This can include trying to figure out what to eat, or not to, when you have a particular diagnosis, have multiple comorbidities, and have a number of different medications.&#xA;One of the most common questions I hear from patients once they’ve started a particular treatment, such as chemotherapy, is, “What can I eat?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Titles Tell Tall Tales, Patients Can Suffer the Consequences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-titles-tell-tall-tales-patients-can-suffer-the-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-titles-tell-tall-tales-patients-can-suffer-the-consequences/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;55% of Telehealth Providers Frustrated With OVERBLOWN Patient Expectations&amp;rdquo;&#xA;I was disappointed to read an inflammatory statement/title without any details on exactly what &amp;ldquo;overblown patient expectations&amp;rdquo; are.&#xA;Digging deeper, this report from United Health Group states: &amp;ldquo;Looking inward, providers saw similar value for themselves in telehealth. Asked how they would describe telehealth, majority of respondents (69%) used the word convenient. Another 28% described virtual care as frustrating.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Sounds like we are talking about of the 28% of providers that described telehealth care as &amp;ldquo;frustrating&amp;rdquo; then 55% (of the 28%) stated that managing patient expectations for their virtual visit was their key frustration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Cancer Day 2022: Eliminating Patient Administrative Burden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/world-cancer-day-2022-eliminating-patient-administrative-burden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/world-cancer-day-2022-eliminating-patient-administrative-burden/</guid>
      <description>February 4, 2022 is World Cancer Day. Too many patients struggle with severe barriers to accessing the care they need. These barriers and delays in care are documented to result in poor outcomes, progressive, advanced disease, as well as inhumane grief, suffering, and death.&#xA;This is unacceptable.&#xA;All patients should have the right to access the care they need to obtain a proper cancer diagnosis and treatment plan.&#xA;All patients should have the right to access the information, tools, and technology they need to make informed, educated decisions about their care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loss of (Already) Limited Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/loss-of-already-limited-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/loss-of-already-limited-time/</guid>
      <description>Patients diagnosed with life-altering, life-limiting diagnoses have a different outlook on life. That outlook may draw a line directly to one’s impeding mortality. Imagine having your anticipated life and time on this Earth cut drastically by an earth-shattering diagnosis, such as cancer or ALS. One’s remaining time should be maximized to the fullest. With the majority of messaging from healthcare’s stakeholders’ amplifying being patient-centered, patient first, and putting the patient at the center of their care, one would think living your best life with a diagnosis is the case.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surprise! No More Surprise Billing!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/surprise-no-more-surprise-billing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/surprise-no-more-surprise-billing/</guid>
      <description>The cost of care and services that a patient may receive is one of the murkiest areas of healthcare. There&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of mind-blowing stories of exorbitant bills that people have received of surprise bills after an emergency room visit, surgery, or even childbirth. This New Year&amp;rsquo;s brought the dawn of a new day and (hopefully) the end of surprise billing.&#xA;Everyone needs to be aware of the No Surprises Act that went into effect on January 1, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Patient Advocacy Goes Global</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-patient-advocacy-goes-global/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-patient-advocacy-goes-global/</guid>
      <description>It was an honor to discuss Innovation in Patient Engagement From the Patient &amp;amp; Carepartner Perspective at the 9th Global Digital Health Partnership Summit.&#xA;Understanding the patient is of essence and yet the word “patient” is one of the most misunderstood words in healthcare’s vocabulary. There is a patient life experience continuum that best captures what it means to live life as a patient where there are 5 categories of being a patient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HLTH2021 Top 8 Insights from the Patient and Carepartner Perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hlth2021-top-8-insights-from-the-patient-and-carepartner-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hlth2021-top-8-insights-from-the-patient-and-carepartner-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Attending HLTH 2021 in-person in Boston solidified that there is no comparison between attending live vs. virtual conferences. While content and presentations can be solid both virtually or in-person, it is the energy of the connections that are made between scheduled presentations and the conversations that are shared throughout that move the needle.&#xA;After reflecting on all the proceedings, the conversations, and the experiences at HLTH 2021, head over to The Health Care Blog for my to eight insights on the event from the patient and carepartner perspective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinktober</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/pinktober/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/pinktober/</guid>
      <description>It’s October, or Pinktober, as we witness the transformation of basically everything, from tortilla chips, to dogs, clothes, athletes uniforms, billboards, feather boas, and all of social media for breast cancer awareness month. It’s time to refresh the message.&#xA;We are aware of breast cancer. What many aren’t aware of is that a specific type of breast cancer, metastatic breast cancer (MBC), has no cure. It will kill every single person diagnosed with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Decision Support (CDS): Accessing Data You Don&#39;t Even Know Exists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/clinical-decision-support-cds-accessing-data-you-dont-even-know-exists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/clinical-decision-support-cds-accessing-data-you-dont-even-know-exists/</guid>
      <description>In a recent WIRED article, The Pain Was Unbearable. So Why Did Doctors Turn Her Away?, Kathryn, who was hospitalized due to complications and suffering from her endometriosis, was denied pain medication for her excruciating condition.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think you are aware of how high some scores are in your chart,&amp;rdquo; the woman said. &amp;ldquo;Considering the prescriptions you&amp;rsquo;re on, it&amp;rsquo;s quite obvious that you need help that is not pain-related.&amp;rdquo; According to the article, Kathryn was unexpectedly abruptly discharged from the hospital while still in poorly controlled pain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Message Are You Sending?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-message-are-you-sending/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-message-are-you-sending/</guid>
      <description>Being successful at patient engagement is high on the lists of many healthcare delivery organizations, practices, and providers.&#xA;Recently I required extensive testing and care for some concerning symptoms that raised red flags. Appointments with the appropriate specialists were scheduled. Tests and imaging were ordered and completed; the waiting game for test results and answers began.&#xA;The clock ticked. The sun rose and set. The symptoms continued. The anxiety climbed higher and higher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom as a Patient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/freedom-as-a-patient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/freedom-as-a-patient/</guid>
      <description>With the celebration of the birth of our country approaching, we recognize, especially after living through a historical, global pandemic, that we are blessed with many freedoms. The COVID-19 pandemic showed us the good, the bad, the ugly, and the unfathomable. We must amplify the good and strive for inclusivity and equality. What would this look like in health care? What does freedom mean as a patient?&#xA;As a patient, freedom means access to affordable, safe, compassionate care that preserves dignity and the quality of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Want Surveys; I Want Solutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/i-dont-want-surveys-i-want-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/i-dont-want-surveys-i-want-solutions/</guid>
      <description>As a patient, the primary carepartner to 2 disabled adults, and a patient advocate to countless individuals, my life is inseparable from encounters in health care. From routine care, to urgent care, to emergency care, to life saving measures, to do not resuscitates, to active death care, and the mystery and heavy grief of death, no two moments are ever really alike. However, the barriers, shortcomings, and opportunities for improvement glaringly overlap and stick out over and over again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Blocking Rules: What’s USCDI Have To Do With It?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/information-blocking-rules-whats-uscdi-have-to-do-with-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/information-blocking-rules-whats-uscdi-have-to-do-with-it/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it’s hard to keep track of every important resource, reference, and article. With all the buzz about the Information Blocking Rules, we’re here to make things a little easier.&#xA;What is Information Blocking?&#xA;There’s a broad spectrum of things that amount to “info blocking,” but in a nutshell, information blocking is when patients can’t get a copy of or access to their medical records when they request them, with some exceptions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let Us Back In</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/let-us-back-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/let-us-back-in/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, I was escorted out of a local hospital by a hospital security guard.&#xA;I was helping a patient who was rushed to the emergency room with excruciating pain. COVID-19 was surging in New Jersey. Hospitals in Bergen and Essex counties were crowded. But this patient needed me at her bedside. I knew all of the details and intricacies of her care and medical history. I grabbed all of her medical records in a binder, grabbed a mask, and met her at the emergency room.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Divide Within</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-digital-divide-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-digital-divide-within/</guid>
      <description>Lack of interoperability, HIPAA misunderstandings, and COVID-19 No Visitor Policies have created an overwhelming digital divide within the traditional four walls of medicine across the nation.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you: &amp;ldquo;innovative, award-winning, world-class, transformative, patient-centered&amp;rdquo; health care delivery organizations.&#xA;Patients who are in the hospital in critical care situations are unable to access their medical information and records in real-time. Their primary carepartners, families, and advocates have been prohibited from the bedside due to COVID-19 No Visitor Policies, leading to lack of communication, breakdowns in trust, and uninformed decision making.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worse than the Stone Age: Stuck in the Paper Age</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/worse-than-the-stone-age-stuck-in-the-paper-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/worse-than-the-stone-age-stuck-in-the-paper-age/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping mom clean out years of paperwork.&#xA;I came across a medical record request from her health plan, circa 1995.&#xA;25+ years later, many doctors, hospitals, &amp;amp; healthcare delivery organizations are stuck in 1995.&#xA;This is why I co-founded Unblock Health: a 1st in class digital patient access front door that is meticulously designed from the patient &amp;amp; carepartner perspective while deeply rooted in strategic business operations, all things interoperability, HIPAA, smart on FHIR, and the future of care where patients are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Right to Inspect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-right-to-inspect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-right-to-inspect/</guid>
      <description>HIPAA grants individuals the right of access and the right to inspect one’s medical and health information within designated record sets maintained by HIPAA covered entities.&#xA;The right to inspect one’s medical records is not frequently discussed.&#xA;Why would someone ask to inspect their or their loved one’s medical record? What if you don’t want an actual copy of the records, but you just need to see them?&#xA;In the real world, the story is always the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sick Enough to Die &amp; the Last to Know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sick-enough-to-die--the-last-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sick-enough-to-die--the-last-to-know/</guid>
      <description>In a culture, society, and democracy that protects freedom of speech, we do a terrible job of talking about the one inevitable thing that unifies us all: death. Openly speaking about death is a rarity and often taboo. One word of advice goes out to doctors:&#xA;There are thousands and thousands of patients across the nation who are sick enough to die and don’t know. Diagnoses are delivered without an explanation of the severity and gravity of the situation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medication Reconciliation: Scarier Than All of Halloween&#39;s Horrors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/medication-reconciliation-scarier-than-all-of-halloweens-horrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/medication-reconciliation-scarier-than-all-of-halloweens-horrors/</guid>
      <description>Adverse drug events (ADE) are a leading cause of patient harm and death worldwide. Almost 70% of patients&amp;rsquo; medication histories noted upon patient admission to hospital have at least one error, with 30 – 80% of patients having a discrepancy between the medicines ordered in hospital and those they take at home. Here is one patient example of the dangers and frustrations of poor medication reconciliation.&#xA;In preparation for an upcoming surgery, a patient &amp;amp; their carepartner followed up with all the patient&amp;rsquo;s care team and the patient&amp;rsquo;s primary care physician (PCP) to discuss the patient&amp;rsquo;s upcoming surgery &amp;amp; medications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over My Dead Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/over-my-dead-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/over-my-dead-body/</guid>
      <description>If you died today, who would you want to have access, or not, to your medical records? The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) ensures that personal health information (PHI) is not wrongfully used, improperly accessed, or shared. Did you know that HIPAA also protects an individual’s right to privacy for up to 50 years after their death?&#xA;There are many reasons why loved ones may need access to a deceased individual’s medical records.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do You Want To Know A Secret?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/do-you-want-to-know-a-secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/do-you-want-to-know-a-secret/</guid>
      <description>As consumers, we are encouraged to review a copy of our credit report each year. What’s the big deal about reviewing one’s credit report regularly? Your credit report may directly impact your ability to secure a loan, obtain a credit card, lease an apartment, qualify to buy a home and the respective mortgage rates, purchasing or leasing a car, and even a job application. Checking your credit report can help with financial planning, committing to responsible financial and purchasing behaviors, as well as helping spot identity theft.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now Where Do I Put Them?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/now-where-do-i-put-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/now-where-do-i-put-them/</guid>
      <description>It’s great to raise awareness about medical records and one’s right of access by HIPAA. People naturally begin asking more involved questions, which is a good thing! One question we at Unblock Health get quite frequently is:&#xA;Once you get a copy of your medical records, where can I as a patient or carepartner store them electronically? Do you have an app for that?&#xA;Unblock Health is not a personal health record (PHR).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Ways Patients Request Medical Records &amp; Their Health Information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/20-ways-patients-request-medical-records--their-health-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/20-ways-patients-request-medical-records--their-health-information/</guid>
      <description>The concept of patient access is often spoken about very matter-of-factly, &amp;ldquo;just request a copy of your records&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;patients have a right to access their medical records&amp;rdquo;, as if it was a straight-forward, standardized process.&#xA;There is a significant difference between technical interoperability from a vendor and systems standpoint and the real-world interoperability that supports the workflows of a patient navigating their care and their life with a diagnosis or diagnoses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telemedicine &amp; Patient Data Access: Pandemically Perfect Together</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/telemedicine--patient-data-access-pandemically-perfect-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/telemedicine--patient-data-access-pandemically-perfect-together/</guid>
      <description>For the last 5 years, telemedicine has been predicted to be the key to transforming health care. COVID19 gave the understudy a coveted, centerstage role, removing more red tape in a matter of weeks than in the last 5 years.&#xA;With many states practicing social distancing and sheltering at home, caregivers, patients, and carepartners needed to rapidly pivot and adjust to ensure continuity of care.&#xA;In hotspot areas, such as in NJ and NY, health care providers escalated telemedicine implementation efforts to deploy virtual care on the scale of weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buckle In</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/buckle-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/buckle-in/</guid>
      <description>When we rung in the New Year, many called the decade upon us the New Roaring 20’s. March 2020 required a seatbelt buckled in tight.&#xA;Coronavirus became a regular part of our daily vocabulary. Positive cases began to rise on the West and East coast. For the 1st time in 58 years, HIMSS was cancelled due to the coronavirus. The heavily anticipated rules were released. Handshakes &amp;amp; hugs were replaced with elbow bumps and head nods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is an Amazon delivery tracked better than a newly diagnosed cancer patient’s medical records request?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-is-an-amazon-delivery-tracked-better-than-a-newly-diagnosed-cancer-patients-medical-records-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-is-an-amazon-delivery-tracked-better-than-a-newly-diagnosed-cancer-patients-medical-records-request/</guid>
      <description>Current patient medical records requests workflows at health systems, hospitals, cancer centers, and physician practices pose significant barriers to patient continuity of care, patient safety, patient outcomes, and, most importantly, trust.&#xA;Our health care ecosystem loves to boast about &amp;ldquo;innovation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;placing the patient at the center of their care&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;empowering patients&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;enabling consumerism&amp;rdquo;. The problem is that many healthcare delivery organizations (HDOs) do a remarkably poor job with the most visible of patient services: initiating, tracking, and resolving medical records requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Errors &amp; Omissions in Your Medical Records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-dangers-of-errors--omissions-in-your-medical-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-dangers-of-errors--omissions-in-your-medical-records/</guid>
      <description>So you get a copy of your medical records &amp;amp; dive in, reading line by line, trying to make sense of your new lung cancer diagnosis.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Wait a second, this doesn’t sound right. This is a mistake. I don’t have a history of a heart condition &amp;amp; I don’t smoke cigarettes&amp;rdquo;, you mutter to yourself.&#xA;You call your oncologist’s office to report the mistake you found &amp;amp; ask to have it updated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When a Failing Heart Faces Information Blocking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-a-failing-heart-faces-information-blocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-a-failing-heart-faces-information-blocking/</guid>
      <description>A 65 year old patient with multiple comorbidities has been in &amp;amp; out of the hospital with what has recently been diagnosed as advanced congestive heart failure. The patient &amp;amp; family are advised to seek a 2nd opinion immediately to both confirm the diagnosis as well as to see if the patient is a potential candidate for a specific, last resort procedure. If the patient is deemed not a candidate for the surgery, at home hospice is advised to be urgently pursued.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Social Media Got to Do With It?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/whats-social-media-got-to-do-with-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/whats-social-media-got-to-do-with-it/</guid>
      <description>Patients rely heavily on peer-to-peer health support through various social media channels, such as Twitter.Social media channels, like Twitter, are a conduit for exposing shortcomings and complaints, as well as celebrating good deeds and jobs well done.&#xA;Nothing goes viral faster than examples of human beings being taken advantage of or falling victim to broken practices and policies.&#xA;Cries of despair coming from sick patients who are being taken advantage of, receiving sub-par care, and forced to deal with unlawful, discriminatory practices are often very quickly shared and frowned upon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isn’t HIPAA Enough?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/isnt-hipaa-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/isnt-hipaa-enough/</guid>
      <description>We MUST level the playing field so patients can fight back when faced with data blocking and lack of transparency.&#xA;It’s only a matter of time until it happens to you or your loved one. When you are dealing with a life-altering, earth-shattering diagnosis and you can’t get access to your medical records, it’s an absolute disaster. Trust us. We know professionally and personally. Together, we can eliminate data blocking, enhance information integrity, drive transparency, and truly empower patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Value of Unblock Health?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-is-the-value-of-unblock-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-is-the-value-of-unblock-health/</guid>
      <description>Data blocking and lack of transparency are 2 of the biggest detriments to not only patient empowerment and engagement, but also to patient care, safety, the patient experience, and consumerism.&#xA;Point of care is in a state of dynamic metamorphosis. Gone are the days where doctors only know best. There is a clear shift from paternalistic to participatory medicine, where patients are not only demanding the driver’s seat to their care, but are also hitting the accelerator and driving through any barriers in their way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Unblock Health?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-is-unblock-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-is-unblock-health/</guid>
      <description>Unblock Health is a first-in-class patient advocacy tool designed for patients and consumers who are determined to be empowered in their health care journey and are no longer willing to accept traditional barriers to their information. Unblock Health is armed and ready to address common, real-world, unmet needs patients, their carepartners, and consumers face daily.&#xA;Unblock Health is designed to:&#xA;hold healthcare organizations &amp;amp; care providers accountable when they do not release medical records in a timely, HIPAA compliant manner, while carefully tracking the process of interactions needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Birth of Unblock Health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-birth-of-unblock-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 06:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-birth-of-unblock-health/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year 2020! With a new year and new decade upon us, we’d like to tell you the story of how Unblock Health was born.&#xA;Once upon a time, at HIT Expo 2018 in sunny New Orleans, a board-certified patient advocate and a health IT thought leader got to talking about patient unmet needs. The advocate fervently emphasized the struggles patients and their loved ones faced due to lack of interoperability, rampant data blocking, and little to no transparency while trying to navigate their life-altering diagnoses.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
