<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CNBC on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/cnbc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CNBC on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 03:48:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/cnbc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amazon already knows a lot about me, but One Medical takes it to a whole new level</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/amazon-already-knows-a-lot-about-me--but-one-medical-takes-it-to-a-whole-new-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 03:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/amazon-already-knows-a-lot-about-me--but-one-medical-takes-it-to-a-whole-new-level/</guid>
      <description>And while there are strict regulations for how that data can be used, consumers can reasonably ask what happens if a company like Amazon were to break the rules.&#xA;Read on cnbc.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. hospitals scramble to adopt new HHS coronavirus data system, some states see &#39;data blackout&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/u-s--hospitals-scramble-to-adopt-new-hhs-coronavirus-data-system--some-states-see--data-blackout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 10:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/u-s--hospitals-scramble-to-adopt-new-hhs-coronavirus-data-system--some-states-see--data-blackout/</guid>
      <description>This is important because current hospitalization data had become the most reliable indicator of the severity of outbreaks in different states, the group said. Unfortunately, now were not sure if some of the erratic changes in hospitalizations that were seeing are due to reporting problems or real changes on the ground.&#xA;Read on cnbc.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why, in the midst of a U.S. health crisis, there are major challenges for doctors to access patient records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/why--in-the-midst-of-a-u-s--health-crisis--there-are-major-challenges-for-doctors-to-access-patient-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/why--in-the-midst-of-a-u-s--health-crisis--there-are-major-challenges-for-doctors-to-access-patient-records/</guid>
      <description>Heres a small sampling of the problems caused by the lack of interoperability. All of that adds complexity and cost to an already overburdened health-care system.Physicians often find themselves ordering duplicate tests, which is a hassle for patients and a major source of unnecessary costs.Patients might see delays in care as their doctors try to aggregate their medical information.It keeps patients feeling captive in a system, because its a burden for them to go to another hospital that uses a different medical record system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epic and about 60 hospital chains come out against rules that would make it easier to share medical info</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/epic-and-about-60-hospital-chains-come-out-against-rules-that-would-make-it-easier-to-share-medical-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 03:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/epic-and-about-60-hospital-chains-come-out-against-rules-that-would-make-it-easier-to-share-medical-info/</guid>
      <description>Here is the full list of health systems and health companies that signed the letter, not including those who chose to send their own:Access Community Health Centers; Community Health Center Network; Altru Health System; Atrius Health; Adventist Health Portland; Affirmant Health Partners; Lovelace Health System; Arc; UT Health Athens; Ardent Health Services; Bay Health; Buffalo Medical Group; Christie Clinic; Deaconess Health System; Genesis Healthcare System; Catholic Health; Community Health Network; Exact Sciences, Group Health Cooperative, South Central Wisconsin; Charlotte Eye Ear Nose &amp;amp; Throat Associates; Confluence Health; Fresenius Medical Care; Gundersen Health System; Guthrie; HonorHealth; Institute for Family Health; Mercy; UnityPoint Health; Hospital Sisters; HSHS Wisconsin; Iowa Specialty Hospitals &amp;amp; Clinics; Mercy Care; MVHS; HSHS St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epic&#39;s CEO is urging hospital customers to oppose rules that would make it easier to share medical info</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/epic-s-ceo-is-urging-hospital-customers-to-oppose-rules-that-would-make-it-easier-to-share-medical-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 14:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/epic-s-ceo-is-urging-hospital-customers-to-oppose-rules-that-would-make-it-easier-to-share-medical-info/</guid>
      <description>The email, which was written by Epic CEO Judy Faulkner and addressed to CEOs and presidents of hospital systems, urges recipients to sign a letter alongside Epic that voices disapproval for rules the Department of Health and Human Services proposed in 2019. These rules aim to make it easy for patients to access their health information at no cost, and make it more challenging for companies to block access to that information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hospital execs say they are getting flooded with requests for your health data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/hospital-execs-say-they-are-getting-flooded-with-requests-for-your-health-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 04:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/hospital-execs-say-they-are-getting-flooded-with-requests-for-your-health-data/</guid>
      <description>But hospital execs worry that this data may be used in unintended ways, and not always in the patients best interest.&#xA;Read on cnbc.com</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
