<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare IT Today on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthcare-it-today/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare IT Today on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 14:31:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/healthcare-it-today/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>21st Century Cures Act, ROI (Release of Information), and HIMs Role</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/21st-century-cures-act--roi--release-of-information--and-him-s-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 14:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/21st-century-cures-act--roi--release-of-information--and-him-s-role/</guid>
      <description>As weve covered before, this is a big shift for many healthcare organizations to immediately share health information with patients. Not only is this a lift technically, but its probably a bigger lift culturally for many healthcare organizations.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delays to Information Blocking and Health IT Certification in 21st Century Cures Act Final Rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/delays-to-information-blocking-and-health-it-certification-in-21st-century-cures-act-final-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 14:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/delays-to-information-blocking-and-health-it-certification-in-21st-century-cures-act-final-rule/</guid>
      <description>The big news in the world of Health IT today is ONCs announcement of the Cures Act Final rule which includes some delays to the information blocking and health IT certification requirements.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Healthcare Interoperability a Reality with Drew Ivan from Lyniate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/making-healthcare-interoperability-a-reality-with-drew-ivan-from-lyniate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/making-healthcare-interoperability-a-reality-with-drew-ivan-from-lyniate/</guid>
      <description>Along with the above topics, I loved how Drew Ivan framed out multiple definitions of interoperability including: organizational interoperability, device interoperability, cross-organizational interoperability, and patient interoperability. Check out the video interview below to hear how he framed it and how you can help make interopability a reality in your organization.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Executives COVID-19 Challenges via KLAS Survey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/healthcare-executives-covid-19-challenges-via-klas-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/healthcare-executives-covid-19-challenges-via-klas-survey/</guid>
      <description>Although, it was interesting to see interoperability, real-time data analytics, and surveillance on the chart as well. What might be even more challenging is that most healthcare organizations were dealing with all of the above all at once during COVID-19.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Teladoc Founder, Michael Gorton</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/interview-with-teladoc-founder--michael-gorton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/interview-with-teladoc-founder--michael-gorton/</guid>
      <description>We all had to be impressed by the merger of Teladoc with Livongo in an $18.5 billion telehealth deal recently, but the road to overnight COVID-19 success has a lot more to the story. In partnership with Dallas Startup Week, I was able to sit down with Michael Gorton, Founder and Former CEO and Chairman of Teladoc, to talk through some of the early telehealth experiences he had at Teladoc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Intake Paperwork and Patient Consent  Telehealth Features Series</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/patient-intake-paperwork-and-patient-consent---telehealth-features-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 14:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/patient-intake-paperwork-and-patient-consent---telehealth-features-series/</guid>
      <description>A digitally integrated patient intake form is a better workflow for everyone involved and more accurate since the patient can often complete the forms at home, at their speed, and with access to all the info they need to complete the forms.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIMSS 2021 Conference Officially Moved to August 9-13 in Las Vegas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/himss-2021-conference-officially-moved-to-august-9-13-in-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/himss-2021-conference-officially-moved-to-august-9-13-in-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>As we reported previously, the HIMSS 2021 conference is officially being moved to August. It will still be held in Las Vegas at the Sands EXPO Center, but now shifted to the summer August 9-13, 2021. In a press briefing today, Hal Wolf, CEO of HIMSS mentioned that they have secured additional space to accommodate social distancing or other changes that may be needed.The obvious concern for August in Las Vegas is the heat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Fax Apps and HIPAA Compliance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/mobile-fax-apps-and-hipaa-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 13:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/mobile-fax-apps-and-hipaa-compliance/</guid>
      <description>Fax represents a large amount of data that is shared between hospitals, doctors, insurance companies, and other healthcare organizations. As we know, digital cloud fax is highly secure, flexible, and easy to use. For organizations that are sending and receiving Protected Health Information (PHI) and other confidential data, however, special precautions need to be taken, especially with regard to the use of mobile devices.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EHR-Based CPOE Tools Miss Many Dangerous Medication Interactions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ehr-based-cpoe-tools-miss-many-dangerous-medication-interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 18:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ehr-based-cpoe-tools-miss-many-dangerous-medication-interactions/</guid>
      <description>Given that many hospitals still rely on EHR-based CPOE systems provided by the systems vendor, its troubling to hear that patients could be at such risk. The current level of dangerous medication errors which are apparently slipping through the cracks is unacceptable.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voice Only Telehealth Reimbursement, PT Telehealth Reimbursement, and Many More Regulatory Changes from CMS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/voice-only-telehealth-reimbursement--pt-telehealth-reimbursement--and-many-more-regulatory-changes-from-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/voice-only-telehealth-reimbursement--pt-telehealth-reimbursement--and-many-more-regulatory-changes-from-cms/</guid>
      <description>A big change was the reimbursement of audio only telehealth which also applies retroactively to March 1, 2020:CMS previously announced that Medicare would pay for certain services conducted by audio-only telephone between beneficiaries and their doctors and other clinicians. Now, CMS is broadening that list to include many behavioral health and patient education services. CMS is also increasing payments for these telephone visits to match payments for similar office and outpatient visits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CMS, ONC, and OIG Regulatory Updates Including Information Blocking Enforcement Details</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/cms--onc--and-oig-regulatory-updates-including-information-blocking-enforcement-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 21:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/cms--onc--and-oig-regulatory-updates-including-information-blocking-enforcement-details/</guid>
      <description>OIG Information Blocking Enforcement Proposed RuleThe largest news is probably that coming out of OIG related to the previously announced Information Blocking Rule in the 21st Century Cures Act. This proposed rule would outline the civil money penalties OIG can enforce against those in healthcare who are doing what ONC has termed Information Blocking.In other words, this is the proposed enforcement of the 21st Century Cures Act Information Blocking provisions. You can read the proposed information blocking rule from OIG that is published on the Federal Register.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Epic Building Its Own Telehealth Solution Using Twilio?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/is-epic-building-its-own-telehealth-solution-using-twilio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 15:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/is-epic-building-its-own-telehealth-solution-using-twilio/</guid>
      <description>A source of Healthcare IT Today recently reached out to let us know that Epic is working to develop their own Epic telehealth offering. The source told us that Epic was working with Twilios newly launched HIPAA compliant video application in order to offer their own telehealth solution within Epic. Word is that Epic has already started offering this solution to provider organizations and is an interesting move for Epic whos largely touted the built in Verona approach to software development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIPAA Penalties Suspended for Telehealth During COVID-19 National Emergency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/hipaa-penalties-suspended-for-telehealth-during-covid-19-national-emergency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 14:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/hipaa-penalties-suspended-for-telehealth-during-covid-19-national-emergency/</guid>
      <description>A covered health care provider that wants to use audio or video communication technology to provide telehealth to patients during the COVID-19 nationwide public health emergency can use any non-public facing remote communication product that is available to communicate with patients. This exercise of discretion applies to telehealth provided for any reason, regardless of whether the telehealth service is related to the diagnosis and treatment of health conditions related to COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#HIMSS20 Has Been Cancelled</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/himss20-has-been-cancelled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 12:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/himss20-has-been-cancelled/</guid>
      <description>Update: HIMSS has published a HIMSS Cancellation FAQ Were sorry to report that the HIMSS 2020 annual conference in Orlando has been cancelled. Heres the email that was sent out by HI&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Ways Practices Are Investing in Patient Experience Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/8-ways-practices-are-investing-in-patient-experience-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 12:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/8-ways-practices-are-investing-in-patient-experience-now/</guid>
      <description>Patients want and deserve access to their medical records. The argument that patients will not understand or will misinterpret the information in their records is no longer an acceptable excuse for preventing access. In fact, the government is about to set rules that may penalize healthcare organizations and software companies that block access to medical information (see info blocking).&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texting Patients Is OK Under HIPAA, as long as you</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/texting-patients-is-ok-under-hipaa--as-long-as-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/texting-patients-is-ok-under-hipaa--as-long-as-you/</guid>
      <description>In its 2016 guidance, the OCR set a $ 6.50 limit (inclusive of all labor, supplies, and postage) for health care providers that do not want to go through the process of calculating actual or average allowable costs for requests for electronic copies of PHI maintained electronically.The federal requirement to recover actual costs, or a flat fee of $6.50, supersedes state laws that allowed providers to charge for medical record searches and per-page fees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Google Restore the Joy of Caregiving?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/can-google--restore-the-joy-of-caregiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 13:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/can-google--restore-the-joy-of-caregiving/</guid>
      <description>Certainly, Googles demo asserts that they can more effectively access and display data across multiple organizations which we all know would be great. However, it doesnt share a compelling case for how theyve really solved the healthcare interoperability problem. Remember that the problem is not a technical one, but a business one. Does a slicker interface do anything to solve the business problem here? Not even close.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Put Care Partners on the Map</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/put-care-partners-on-the-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/put-care-partners-on-the-map/</guid>
      <description>The more I think about it because we can know when caregiving begins or escalates, its a discrete moment in time when we can both give the caregiver the support and resources they need to prevent serious health issues and help ensure patients get good care and support at home.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escaping From an Energy Canyon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/escaping-from-an-energy-canyon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 13:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/escaping-from-an-energy-canyon/</guid>
      <description>So if patients are stuck in energy canyons, connecting with peers may be one of the best ways to give each other the energy boost needed to spark action.&#xA;Read on healthcareittoday.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Actions Hospitals Should Take Now to Prepare for Interoperability</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/5-actions-hospitals-should-take-now-to-prepare-for-interoperability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 13:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/5-actions-hospitals-should-take-now-to-prepare-for-interoperability/</guid>
      <description>Focus on interoperability for health data systems has increased recently given multiple proposed Department of Health and Human Services regulations addressing how health data is shared. Healthcare providers are a primary source of health data and should be aware of how to prepare for these new regulations. While each hospital has its unique approach to managing its health data and sharing of that information, there are actions all hospitals can take to prepare for heightened expectations for health data interoperability.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
