<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Federal Trade Commission on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/source/federal-trade-commission/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Federal Trade Commission on Patient Advocacy Suite | Healthcare Advocate Services | Unblock Health</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 20:46:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/source/federal-trade-commission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Protecting the privacy of health information: A bakers dozen takeaways from FTC cases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/protecting-the-privacy-of-health-information--a-baker-s-dozen-takeaways-from-ftc-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 20:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/protecting-the-privacy-of-health-information--a-baker-s-dozen-takeaways-from-ftc-cases/</guid>
      <description>In the past few months, the FTC has announced case after case involving consumers sensitive health data, alleging violations of both Section 5 of the FTC Act and the FTCs Health Breach Notification Rule. The privacy of health information is top of mind for consumers and so itstop of mind for the FTC. Companies collecting or using health data, listen up. There are a number of key messages from BetterHelp, GoodRx, Premom, Vitagene, and other FTC matters that you need to hear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FTC Explores Rules Cracking Down on Commercial Surveillance and Lax Data Security Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/ftc-explores-rules-cracking-down-on-commercial-surveillance-and-lax-data-security-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/ftc-explores-rules-cracking-down-on-commercial-surveillance-and-lax-data-security-practices/</guid>
      <description>The Federal Trade Commission today announced it is exploring rules to crack down on harmful commercial surveillance and lax data security. Commercial surveillance is the business of collecting, analyzing, and profiting from information about people.Mass surveillance has heightened the risks and stakes of data breaches, deception, manipulation, and other abuses. The FTCs Advance Notice of Proposed Rulemaking seeks public comment on the harms stemming from commercial surveillance and whether new rules are needed to protect peoples privacy and information.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
